driving and sounds
驾驶和声音
th
okay uh... greening class
好吧呃...绿化课
right so we'll come back uh... so before we start the lecture today just want to
是的，所以我们会回来呃...所以在我们今天开始讲座之前只想
remind you right in case some of you uh...
提醒你一下，以防你们中的一些人呃...
may not be aware
可能不知道
so uh... today is twenty second of august so we are supposed to have a lecture in this LT
所以呃...今天是八月二十二号所以我们应该有一个关于这个LT的讲座
which is LT2A
这是 LT2A
but for the next two weeks we'll be having our lectures in this Lee Koon Cheon LT here
但接下来的两周我们将在 Lee Koon Cheon LT 中进行讲座
so this is the LT near Can Thim B
这是 Can Thim B 附近的 LT
okay so just to remind you that
好的，只是提醒你一下
for the next two weeks the lectures will be in Lee Koon Cheon LT
接下来两周的讲座将在 Lee Koon Cheon LT 进行
above or near Can Thim B
Can Thim B 上方或附近
okay and also uh... in case some of you are not aware
好吧，呃……以防万一你们中有些人不知道
right so you can uh... download the lecture notes and some
是的，所以你可以呃...下载讲义和一些
uh... exercises from the uh... folder
呃...来自呃...文件夹的练习
right so from the course folder and also there's some recorded lectures so each week
就在课程文件夹中，还有一些每周录制的讲座
the lectures will be recorded
讲座将被记录
okay so if you want to do some revision you are welcome to
好的，如果您想做一些修改，欢迎您
uh... watch these particular lectures
呃...观看这些特别的讲座
so also from
所以也从
can you all hear me from the back
你们能从后面听到我的声音吗
yeah also from past experience we will
是的，根据过去的经验，我们也会
you know tends to notice that as
你知道往往会注意到
you know the lecture progress
你知道讲座进度
the number of students will start to decrease
学生人数将开始减少
so last week you can see lots of seats are taken this week already there are some
所以上周你可以看到很多座位都被占用了，本周已经有一些座位了
uh... empty seats
呃……空位子
so we expect the train to continue
所以我们预计火车会继续
right so one of the possible reason is that
是的，所以可能的原因之一是
uh... some students told me before they find it
呃...有些学生在找到之前就告诉我了
you know they can watch this recorded lecture
你知道他们可以观看这个录制的讲座
and they can make the speed to 1.5
他们可以将速度提高到1.5
they said that when I speak my pace is a bit slow
他们说我说话的时候步伐有点慢
so if they speed up the
所以如果他们加快
this lecture speed by 1.5 times
本讲课速度提高1.5倍
he can actually cut down one hour so instead of coming here and stay for three hours
他实际上可以减少一个小时，所以不用来这里呆三个小时
you just need to
你只需要
you know spend two hours to watch the recorded lecture
你知道花两个小时观看录制的讲座
okay so anyway that's a joke aside so uh... yeah please continue to come and attend the lecture
好吧，无论如何，这是一个笑话，所以呃...是的，请继续来参加讲座
but just to let you know that there's this recorded lecture that you can watch
但只是想让你知道，你可以观看这个讲座录音
uh... afterwards if you find that there are some
呃...之后如果你发现有一些
uh... concepts that you are not clear with
呃……你不清楚的概念
okay so uh... today we are going to continue on with our lecture so we are going to move on to
好吧，呃...今天我们将继续我们的讲座，所以我们将继续
part two now
现在第二部分
so part two will be mainly dealing with image compression and jpeg standards
所以第二部分将主要处理图像压缩和 jpeg 标准
right so again these are some references should you have any questions that you want to
是的，如果您有任何疑问，这些是一些参考资料
uh... find out more about the
呃...了解更多关于
uh... the topics or the content for this part of the course you can refer to this reference
呃...这部分课程的主题或者内容你可以参考这个参考资料
material
材料
or again you can go to google or use chatgpt to help you to
或者您可以再次访问 google 或使用 chatgpt 来帮助您
improve your learning experience
改善您的学习体验
right okay so in part two these are the outline for the topics that we are going to cover
好的，所以在第二部分中，这些是我们将要讨论的主题的大纲
so first of all we are going to learn some basic terms and concepts
所以首先我们要学习一些基本术语和概念
and afterwards we'll go through the entropy coding
然后我们将进行熵编码
and then we'll learn about some basic image and video compression
然后我们将学习一些基本的图像和视频压缩
okay we'll learn about transform based coding
好的，我们将学习基于变换的编码
and afterwards we'll move on to DCT which is a very popular
然后我们将继续讨论 DCT，这是一种非常流行的方法
uh... you know transform technique that's used in many media compression including
呃...您知道许多媒体压缩中使用的变换技术，包括
jpeg as well as mpeg compression
jpeg 以及 mpeg 压缩
so we'll spend some time to learn about this particular DCT, discrete cosine transform
所以我们将花一些时间来学习这个特殊的 DCT，离散余弦变换
and afterwards we'll learn about the jpeg standards
然后我们将了解 jpeg 标准
so these are the topics that we are going to cover in part two
这些是我们将在第二部分中讨论的主题
right okay so first let's try to go through some basic terms and concepts
好的，首先让我们尝试了解一些基本术语和概念
just to make sure that everyone is on the same page
只是为了确保每个人都在同一页面上
right okay so what is compression
好吧，那么什么是压缩
or coding so in the context of media compression
或在媒体压缩的背景下进行编码
right when we say compression it actually means the same thing as in coding
当我们说压缩时，它实际上与编码中的意思相同
so in this article course
所以在这篇文章课程中
when we refer to compression it means the same thing as coding or encoding
当我们提到压缩时，它与编码或编码具有相同的含义
they are all the same
他们都是一样的
right so what is the objective of performing compression
是的，那么执行压缩的目的是什么
right so if you think about for typical for example image and video so from
是的，如果您考虑典型的图像和视频，那么来自
last week we just do a simple calculation to see if you have a small video
上周我们只是做了一个简单的计算，看看你是否有一个小视频
right it already require a very large bit rate
是的，它已经需要非常大的比特率
okay hundreds of uh...
好吧，几百个呃……
megabits per second so therefore there's a very strong motivation for us to
每秒兆位，因此我们有非常强烈的动机
perform the compression
执行压缩
because if you don't compress it then it's very hard for us to store
因为如果不压缩它我们就很难存储
in some uh... storage devices or transmit over the network
在一些呃...存储设备中或通过网络传输
so therefore there's a strong motivation for us to perform compression
因此我们有很强的动机去执行压缩
because without compression
因为没有压缩
right the data, original data is just too demanding in terms of
对数据，原始数据要求太高了
storage and bandwidth requirement
存储和带宽要求
so therefore we need to perform compression so what's the objective of it
所以我们需要执行压缩，那么它的目的是什么
is to reduce the number of bits
就是减少位数
that's needed to represent the information
表示信息所需的
okay so i think the motivation is quite straightforward
好吧，我认为动机很简单
so what you have is that you have some input data
所以你拥有的是一些输入数据
so this input data can be for example text, it can be audio, it can be image, it can be video
所以这个输入数据可以是文本，可以是音频，可以是图像，可以是视频
but in the context of this particular course
但在这个特定课程的背景下
our focus mainly will be on
我们的重点将主要集中在
uh... image and video
呃...图像和视频
right okay because we are talking about video signal processing
好吧，因为我们正在谈论视频信号处理
so we have some input data which can be for example image and video
所以我们有一些输入数据，例如图像和视频
and then you go through the encoder
然后你通过编码器
right so the encoder in this particular context is actually used for compression
是的，所以这个特定上下文中的编码器实际上用于压缩
so we have an original for example image file
所以我们有一个原始的例如图像文件
when we go through the encoder, we try to compress it into a small file
当我们通过编码器时，我们尝试将其压缩成一个小文件
or low bit rate
或低比特率
right so that
对所以
right when the file is small then you can either store it or you can then transmit it
当文件很小时，您可以存储它，也可以传输它
so you can then either store it
这样你就可以存储它
right as an image and video file or you can transmit over the network
作为图像和视频文件，或者您可以通过网络传输
okay so later on, suppose it is a network then at the receiver end
好的，稍后假设它是一个网络然后在接收端
then you need to perform the decoder
那么你需要执行解码器
right so you need to let it go through a decoder
是的，所以你需要让它通过解码器
so this decoder's objective is to perform decompression
所以这个解码器的目标是执行解压缩
so decompression means that you take some compressed bit stream
所以解压缩意味着你需要一些压缩的比特流
and you try to recover the original data
并且您尝试恢复原始数据
so this is the meaning of decompression
这就是减压的意义
and afterwards you have the output data
然后你就得到了输出数据
right so that's the very basic ideas of a data compression
是的，这就是数据压缩的基本思想
framework or pipeline
框架或管道
right okay so next we need to introduce this concept or this term compression ratio
好吧，接下来我们需要介绍这个概念或者这个术语压缩比
but so what is the definitions of a compression ratio
那么压缩比的定义是什么
so the definition of compression ratio is data storage requirement
所以压缩比的定义就是数据存储要求
of the original data over the storage requirement for the compressed data
原始数据超过压缩数据的存储要求
so it's a number of bits or the storage requirement
所以这是位数或存储要求
for the original uncompressed data
对于原始未压缩数据
over the data storage requirement for a compressed data
超过压缩数据的数据存储要求
so by the definition, if your method is performing the compression well
所以根据定义，如果你的方法能够很好地执行压缩
do you think the compression ratio should be greater than one or less than one?
你认为压缩比应该大于1还是小于1？
If you define compression ratio as the data storage requirement for the original data
如果将压缩比定义为原始数据的数据存储要求
over data storage requirement for compressed data,
超过压缩数据的数据存储要求，
and if your method is working properly,
如果你的方法工作正常，
you expect the compression ratio to be greater than one or less than one?
您期望压缩比大于 1 或小于 1？
Greater than one.
大于一。
Because definitely this is the original data storage requirement
因为这肯定是原始的数据存储需求
therefore your compressed data is going to be much smaller.
因此你的压缩数据会小得多。
So it's going to be a larger value over a smaller value.
所以它会是一个较大的值而不是一个较小的值。
Therefore your compression ratio typically should be greater than one.
因此，您的压缩比通常应大于 1。
So therefore the meaning of a compression ratio is quite straightforward.
因此，压缩比的含义非常简单。
It's a matrix or a way for you to measure how much the data has been compressed.
它是一个矩阵或一种测量数据压缩程度的方法。
So it's defined as this B naught,
所以它被定义为这个B无，
which is the number of bits before compression or is the original data storage requirement,
这是压缩前的位数或者是原始数据存储要求，
over B1, which is the number of bits or the storage requirement after the compression.
B1 之上，这是压缩后的位数或存储要求。
So because after compression you expect this number to be smaller than this.
因为压缩后你预计这个数字会比这个小。
Therefore typically for compression ratio it should be greater than one.
因此，通常对于压缩比来说，它应该大于一。
And usually the larger the value, that means the smaller size you can compress it into.
通常该值越大，意味着可以压缩的尺寸越小。
So from the compression perspective you want the value to be as large as possible.
因此，从压缩的角度来看，您希望该值尽可能大。
Okay, so next we are going to touch on some basics on information theory.
好的，接下来我们将讨论信息论的一些基础知识。
So the concept that we are going to introduce is the entropy here.
所以这里我们要引入的概念就是熵。
So this entropy or using this symbol called eta is the measures of the amount of information in some data source.
所以这个熵或者使用这个称为eta的符号是某些数据源中信息量的度量。
Or sometimes it's also an indication of degree of randomness in the data source.
或者有时它也表明数据源的随机性程度。
So the entropy eta for an information source, suppose this information source what you have is that you have a set S,
所以信息源的熵 eta，假设你拥有的这个信息源是你有一个集合 S，
which consists of a number of different symbols, S1 all the way up to Sn.
它由许多不同的符号组成，从 S1 一直到 Sn。
So we are trying to measure this entropy, that means we are trying to measure the amount of information inside
所以我们正在尝试测量这个熵，这意味着我们正在尝试测量内部的信息量
or the degree of randomness inside this particular data source here.
或此处特定数据源内部的随机性程度。
So that's a very formal definition for entropy.
这是熵的一个非常正式的定义。
So for those of you if you have studied digital communication, you should definitely know the equation.
因此，对于那些研究过数字通信的人来说，您一定应该知道这个方程。
So the entropy eta is given by this particular symbol here, H.
因此，熵 eta 由此处的特定符号 H 给出。
The entropy for this set S is defined by this equation here, Pi.
该集合 S 的熵由此处的方程 Pi 定义。
So this Pi here is the probability of each of this particular symbol in this set here.
所以这里的 Pi 是这个集合中每个特定符号的概率。
So this Pi, log Pi with a base of 2, and then you sum up over all the possible symbols in the set.
所以这个 Pi，以 2 为底记录 Pi，然后对集合中所有可能的符号求和。
So that's the definitions of the entropy.
这就是熵的定义。
And afterwards if you can simplify this a little bit, Pi is P to the power of negative 1, you move it down here,
然后如果你能稍微简化一下，Pi 是 P 的负 1 次方，你把它移到这里，
then you can rewrite in this form here.
那么你可以在这里重写这个形式。
So therefore for entropy you can also write it as Pi, log Pi to the base of 2,
因此，对于熵，你也可以将其写为 Pi，将 Pi 记录到 2 的底数，
you sum up over all the symbols in the set and you put a negative sign in front.
你总结了集合中的所有符号，并在前面加上一个负号。
So this is the entropy.
这就是熵。
So as I mentioned before, Pi is the probability of a symbol Si that occurs in this set here.
正如我之前提到的，Pi 是符号 Si 在此集合中出现的概率。
So what is the significance of this particular entropy in the context of compression is that
那么这个特定的熵在压缩的背景下的意义是什么？
entropy is the smallest number of bits on average that you need to represent a symbol.
熵是表示符号所需的平均最小位数。
So for example, now you have a set S, you have many different symbols.
例如，现在你有一个集合 S，你有许多不同的符号。
So on average, the smallest number of bits that you can use to represent this set of symbols is known as entropy.
因此，平均而言，可用于表示这组符号的最小位数称为熵。
So for example, if you are given a particular symbol, a set S with a certain number of symbols,
举例来说，如果给你一个特定的符号，一个包含一定数量符号的集合 S，
say suppose here you have 8 symbols, you can easily use 3 bits to represent it.
假设这里有 8 个符号，您可以轻松地使用 3 位来表示它。
If you want, you can even use 8 bits or 10 bits to represent it.
如果愿意的话，甚至可以用8位或者10位来表示。
So you can use a larger number of bits to represent it.
因此可以使用更多的位数来表示。
But if you want to reduce the number of bits, continue to reduce the number of bits, that is a theoretical lower bound.
但如果要减少位数，就继续减少位数，那就是理论上的下界。
So the theoretical lower bound, the number of bits on average that you need to represent this particular symbol is known as the entropy.
因此，理论上的下界，即表示该特定符号所需的平均位数，称为熵。
So that's another interpretation of the entropy in the context of compression.
这是压缩背景下熵的另一种解释。
Okay, so now we have introduced some basic terms.
好的，现在我们介绍了一些基本术语。
Now we are ready to cover the next topic, which is the entropy coding.
现在我们准备好讨论下一个主题，即熵编码。
So as I mentioned, coding and encoding refer to the same thing.
正如我提到的，编码和编码指的是同一件事。
There's no difference between them.
他们之间没有区别。
Okay, so there's different ways of performing entropy encoding.
好的，有不同的方法来执行熵编码。
So for this course, we will be focusing on Huffman coding,
因此，在本课程中，我们将重点关注霍夫曼编码，
because Huffman coding is one of the most commonly used coding used in media compression,
因为霍夫曼编码是媒体压缩中最常用的编码之一，
either image compression or video compression, and there are corresponding standards,
无论是图像压缩还是视频压缩，都有相应的标准，
such as JPEG standard and the MPEG standard.
例如JPEG标准和MPEG标准。
So therefore, we'll be focusing on Huffman coding here.
因此，我们将在这里重点关注霍夫曼编码。
And also just to make a note, because for this particular class here, the background is actually quite diverse.
另外，我也想说明一下，因为对于这个特殊的班级来说，背景实际上是相当多样化的。
I understand that there are students from SPML, students from communication, students from control, even some students from power, and also CCA.
我了解到有SPML的学生，有传播的学生，有控制的学生，甚至还有一些权力的学生，还有CCA。
So the background is quite diverse.
所以背景是相当多元化的。
So therefore, in order to make sure that everyone understands it,
所以，为了让大家都能理解，
we'll try to cover it in such a way that at least the majority of students will be able to understand.
我们将尽力以至少大多数学生能够理解的方式进行介绍。
So therefore, in case if you're already familiar with some of the concepts,
因此，如果您已经熟悉一些概念，
just take it as a revision or sometimes you may gain a certain new perspective.
只是把它当作一次修订，有时你可能会获得某种新的视角。
Right, okay, so having said that, next let's look at what's the Huffman coding.
好了好了，说了这么多，接下来我们看看什么是哈夫曼编码。
So Huffman coding is the types of variable length coding, or VLCC.
所以哈夫曼编码是可变长度编码的类型，或者VLCC。
So what is the, you can see by this particular term here, variable length coding,
那么什么是，你可以通过这里的这个特定术语看到，可变长度编码，
it does already tell you some indication about what this coding scheme is.
它确实已经告诉您有关此编码方案是什么的一些指示。
So this particular coding scheme means that for different symbols, all right, different symbols, you use different bits to represent this particular symbol.
所以这个特定的编码方案意味着对于不同的符号，好吧，不同的符号，你使用不同的位来表示这个特定的符号。
So symbol is a very general term to describe any kind of a data source that we have.
因此，符号是一个非常通用的术语，用于描述我们拥有的任何类型的数据源。
So to give you an example, if we refer to English, right, English, so most of you know English.
举个例子，如果我们指的是英语，对吧，英语，所以你们大多数人都懂英语。
So English, we have 26 alphabets.
所以英语有 26 个字母。
So if you want, for example, you can use 8 bits to represent each of these particular alphabets.
例如，如果您愿意，您可以使用 8 位来表示每个特定的字母表。
So for each English alphabet, if you want, you can use 8 bits to represent it.
所以对于每个英文字母，如果你愿意的话，你可以用8位来表示它。
It's not a problem.
这不是问题。
But if you do that, it may not be so efficient, right?
但如果你这样做的话，效率可能就不那么高了，对吧？
It may not be so efficient.
可能效率不是那么高。
Okay, another thing about this entropy encoding is that for example, if we take the example of the English, right,
好吧，关于这种熵编码的另一件事是，例如，如果我们以英语为例，对吧，
some actually alphabets or some letters occur more often than the others.
实际上，有些字母或某些字母比其他字母出现的频率更高。
So for example, in English, what are the letters that occur very frequently, very often?
比如说，在英语中，出现得非常频繁的字母是什么？
Can some of you suggest some English letters that occur very often?
你们中的一些人能推荐一些经常出现的英文字母吗？
First, we have the vowel, A-E-I-O-U, those occur very often.
首先，我们有元音，A-E-I-O-U，这些经常出现。
And then if you have the consonant, consonant is like T, I just given you one, T, S, M, yeah,
然后如果你有辅音，辅音就像T，我刚刚给了你一个，T，S，M，是的，
and these are very common kind of a consonant.
这些都是非常常见的辅音。
So therefore, you have these letters which occur very often.
因此，这些字母经常出现。
So for these letters that occur very often, if you want to design certain codes to represent it,
那么对于这些​​经常出现的字母，如果你想设计一定的代码来表示它，
do you think you should use a shorter code work or longer code work to represent it?
您认为应该使用较短的代码工作还是较长的代码工作来表示它？
Shorter code works means you use a smaller number of bits.
较短的代码意味着您使用较少的位数。
Longer code works means that you use a larger number of bits to represent.
更长的代码意味着您使用更多的位数来表示。
So for those letters that occur very often, do you think you should use less letter,
那么对于那些经常出现的字母，你认为你应该少用一些字母吗？
less number of shorter code work or longer code work to represent?
更少的较短代码工作或较长代码工作来表示？
Would you use?
你会用吗？
If they occur so often, because in the context of this particular course is we want to perform compression.
如果它们经常出现，因为在这个特定课程的背景下我们想要执行压缩。
So when we want to perform compression, that means we want to use as few bits as possible to represent our information source.
因此，当我们想要执行压缩时，这意味着我们想要使用尽可能少的位来表示我们的信息源。
So if you know that certain letters occur so often, therefore you should use shorter code work,
因此，如果您知道某些字母经常出现，那么您应该使用较短的代码工作，
that means smaller number of bits or longer number of bits to represent it.
这意味着用更少的位数或更长的位数来表示它。
Shorter code works or smaller number of bits, it's very intuitive.
较短的代码或较少的位数可以工作，这非常直观。
So on the other hand, if you think about it, so for some letters like in English,
另一方面，如果你想一想，对于一些字母，比如英语，
what are the letters that occur very rarely, very infrequently?
很少出现的字母是什么？
Q, Z or Z depending on whether you're American or British.
Q、Z 或 Z 取决于您是美国人还是英国人。
So these are some very rare kind of English letters.
所以这些是一些非常罕见的英文字母。
So for those letters, should you use a longer code work or shorter code work to represent it?
那么对于那些字母，应该用较长的码工还是较短的码工来表示呢？
You should use a longer code work, because they occur so rarely,
你应该使用更长的代码工作，因为它们很少发生，
so you can afford to use a longer code work to represent it.
因此您可以使用更长的代码来表示它。
So therefore, the idea now is quite clear, depending on the probability of how often a letter appears,
因此，现在的想法就很清楚了，取决于一个字母出现的概率，
you assign different code work length to represent this particular letter.
您分配不同的代码工作长度来表示这个特定的字母。
So this idea now is reflected by variable length coding.
所以这个思想现在通过变长编码来体现。
So what it means is that for different symbols or letters, we'll be using different variable,
所以这意味着对于不同的符号或字母，我们将使用不同的变量，
we'll be using different number of bits to represent the letter.
我们将使用不同的位数来表示字母。
Hence the name, variable length coding.
因此得名“可变长度编码”。
So this is as opposed to, for example, just now we say, if you want, we can use 8 bits to represent each letter.
所以这是相对的，比如说刚才我们说，如果你愿意的话，我们可以用8位来表示每个字母。
But if you do that, we don't take into account the probability distribution of the letter.
但如果你这样做，我们就不会考虑字母的概率分布。
So therefore, it's not a very clever way of doing it.
因此，这不是一个非常聪明的方法。
So therefore, the idea now is quite straightforward.
因此，现在的想法非常简单。
So the idea of variable length coding, we have just gone through an example to provide the motivation.
因此，我们刚刚通过一个示例来提供可变长度编码的想法。
So the approach is that higher frequency patterns or symbols are assigned shorter code work.
因此，方法是为较高频率的模式或符号分配较短的代码工作。
Shorter code works means you require smaller number of bits.
较短的代码意味着您需要较少的位数。
So on the other hand, the reverse is also true.
所以从另一方面来说，反之亦然。
That means lower frequency patterns or symbols, you will assign longer code work.
这意味着频率较低的模式或符号，您将分配更长的代码工作。
So the objective of you doing that is that such that on average,
所以你这样做的目标是平均而言，
the number of bits that is required to represent each pattern or symbol will be reduced.
表示每个模式或符号所需的位数将减少。
So on average, the average number of bits to represent a symbol now will be shorter.
因此，平均而言，现在表示符号的平均位数会更短。
So that's the idea of variable length coding.
这就是变长编码的思想。
So in the context of Huffman coding, as I mentioned, typically we use this work symbol to represent
因此，正如我提到的，在霍夫曼编码的背景下，通常我们使用这个工作符号来表示
it's a very general term, symbol.
这是一个非常笼统的术语，符号。
So for example, just now in the context of the English letter, the symbol can be used to represent the letter.
那么比如说刚才在英文字母的上下文中，可以用符号来代表字母。
So in the context of example, if you are trying to perform some image compression,
因此，在示例中，如果您尝试执行一些图像压缩，
you may partition the image into small image patches.
您可以将图像分割成小图像块。
Then the symbol can be used to, for example, represent a small image patch.
然后，该符号可用于表示一个小图像块等。
So therefore, symbol is a very generic term that we use to describe a pattern.
因此，符号是一个非常通用的术语，我们用来描述模式。
Okay, so next we'll use a simple example to explain how do we exactly perform this Huffman coding.
好的，接下来我们将用一个简单的例子来解释我们如何准确地执行这个霍夫曼编码。
So what it means is that given a particular set of symbols with their corresponding probability distribution,
所以这意味着给定一组特定的符号及其相应的概率分布，
we want to generate the code works that can be used to represent this particular set of symbol.
我们想要生成可用于表示这一特定符号集的代码作品。
So that's what we plan to do. This is the objective of Huffman coding.
这就是我们计划做的。这就是霍夫曼编码的目标。
So we take a simple example first.
所以我们先举一个简单的例子。
Suppose this particular example is that we have strings of character like this.
假设这个特定的例子是我们有这样的字符串。
So we can see we have four A's, two B's, one C and one D.
所以我们可以看到我们有 4 个 A、2 个 B、1 个 C 和 1 个 D。
And then we want to generate this Huffman code work set for these sets of letters with this probability distribution.
然后我们要为这些具有这种概率分布的字母集生成霍夫曼代码工作集。
So we can see in this case here, A occurs four times, B occurs two times, C and D occur once.
所以我们可以看到，在这种情况下，A 出现了四次，B 出现了两次，C 和 D 出现了一次。
For each of them, it occurs only one time.
对于每个人来说，这种情况只发生一次。
So therefore, from our understanding, if you want to represent this particular letter A using code work,
因此，根据我们的理解，如果你想使用代码工作来表示这个特定的字母 A，
you want it to have a shorter code work or longer code work?
您希望它有更短的代码工作还是更长的代码工作？
You want it to have shorter code work.
您希望它的代码工作更短。
And which are the symbols that have the longest code work?
哪些符号的代码工作时间最长？
It should be C or D.
应该是C或者D。
So even before we do that, we know that that is the high level intuition.
因此，甚至在我们这样做之前，我们就知道那是高级直觉。
So next, I'm going to go through with you a systematic way of generating the Huffman code work set.
接下来，我将与您一起了解生成霍夫曼代码工作集的系统方法。
So actually, there are many different ways you can do it.
所以实际上，有很多不同的方法可以做到这一点。
But here in this course, we are just going to introduce one way of doing it, which is usually quite a common way of doing it.
但在本课程中，我们仅介绍一种方法，这通常是一种非常常见的方法。
So what we'll do first of all is that we can see that A occurs four times, B two times, C and D occur once each.
所以我们首先要做的是，我们可以看到 A 出现了四次，B 出现了两次，C 和 D 各出现了一次。
So the first thing that we'll do is that we'll write down this particular symbol in the decreasing order of occurrence or the decreasing probability.
因此，我们要做的第一件事就是按照出现次数或概率递减的顺序写下这个特定的符号。
So we write down A, B, C and D. It's because A occurs four times, B is two times, C and D is one time each.
所以我们记下A、B、C、D。因为A出现了四次，B出现了两次，C和D各出现了一次。
So we write it down in the decreasing occurrence, number of occurrence here.
所以我们在这里以出现次数递减的方式写下来。
This C and D, you can actually sort it. It doesn't matter you sort the order.
这个C和D，其实可以排序。排序顺序并不重要。
But no, because in English, C occur before D. So we just happen to write this way.
但不是，因为在英语中，C 出现在 D 之前。所以我们碰巧这样写。
OK, so we write down A, B, C, D. And then next week, we write down the number of occurrence, four, two, one, one here.
好的，所以我们写下 A、B、C、D。然后下周，我们在这里写下出现的次数，四、二、一、一。
So the next thing is that we take those two symbols with the lowest number of occurrence, the C and D, we add them up, write the number.
接下来，我们取出出现次数最少的两个符号 C 和 D，将它们相加，写出数字。
So you can see one plus one, it becomes two.
所以你可以看到一加一，它变成了二。
So once you have this two here, we move it to the next column.
因此，一旦您在这里找到了这两个，我们就把它移到下一列。
But you try to rearrange the next column again in the decreasing orders of occurrence here.
但是您尝试按照此处出现的降序再次重新排列下一列。
So if you add up one and one is two, so two happen to be the same as this number two above.
因此，如果将一加起来等于二，那么二恰好与上面的数字二相同。
So if the number is the same, usually we try not to disturb it so much. We just move it at the bottom.
所以如果数字相同，通常我们尽量不要去打扰它。我们只需将其移动到底部即可。
So now we have this one plus one is two here. So the rest, we just move it over. This A4 and B2, we just move it over.
现在我们有了这个一加一等于二。那么剩下的，我们就把它移过去。这个A4和B2，我们就移过来。
And then afterwards, we repeat the same thing. We take the two smallest occurrence, two and two, add up is four.
然后，我们重复同样的事情。我们取两个最小的出现次数，二加二，加起来是四。
And then four should be the same as this A4, so we just put it at the bottom here. And then the rest, we just move it up here.
然后四个应该和这个A4一样，所以我们就把它放在这里的底部。然后剩下的，我们就把它移到这里。
Okay, so we have done the first step. So the second step is that we assign, we need to assign the bits patterns already.
好的，我们已经完成了第一步。所以第二步是我们分配，我们需要分配位模式。
So for this particular course, because we are following these textbooks, so they assign the bits as in the top branch is one, bottom branch is zero.
因此，对于这个特定的课程，因为我们遵循这些教科书，所以他们分配的位在顶部分支中为 1，底部分支中为 0。
So they assign one zero, one zero, one zero here.
所以他们在这里分配一零，一零，一零。
Okay, so if you want to assign zero one, zero one, zero one, actually it's also okay.
好吧，所以如果你想分配零一，零一，零一，其实也可以。
But for this particular course, let's try to stick to the convention that this book introduced.
但对于这个特定的课程，让我们尝试遵循本书介绍的约定。
So that in the event if I ask a question during the quiz or exam, I don't have to check all the possible version.
这样，如果我在测验或考试期间提出问题，我不必检查所有可能的版本。
So we stick to this particular convention here, one zero, one zero, one zero.
所以我们在这里坚持这个特殊的约定，一零，一零，一零。
Okay, so now we have more or less finished this part already.
好的，现在我们已经或多或少地完成了这一部分。
Okay, and then next is we just try to transfer this symbol, the symbol, right, just before it's being merged.
好的，接下来我们只是尝试在合并之前转移这个符号，对吧。
Just for it, make it easier for us to do the tracking. So A, before it's being merged here, it's here.
就是为了让我们更方便的进行追踪。所以A，在它被合并到这里之前，它就在这里。
And B, you can continue to write here before it's being merged, it's here. And C, and V are here.
还有B，你可以在合并之前继续写在这里，就在这里。 C、V 也在这里。
Okay, so we have done this already. The next thing is that we need to build a Huffman code tree here.
好的，我们已经做到了。接下来我们需要在这里构建一个霍夫曼代码树。
So for this Huffman code tree, we start on top. On top is actually four plus four is eight.
因此，对于这个霍夫曼代码树，我们从顶部开始。上面实际上是四加四等于八。
Just now there's no need. If you want, we can add them up further to become eight.
只是现在还没有必要。如果您愿意，我们可以将它们进一步加起来成为八个。
But it's actually not really necessary.
但实际上并不是真的有必要。
So anyway, we start with the root node of eight, which is four plus four, eight.
所以无论如何，我们从根节点 8 开始，即四加四，八。
Right, okay, for this Huffman code tree branching, okay, the left branch we assign a bit of zero,
好的，好的，对于这个霍夫曼代码树分支，好的，左分支我们分配一个零位，
and the right branch we assign a bit of one. So it's zero and one here.
右边的分支我们分配一点1。所以这里是零和一。
So you can see this zero here corresponds to this value four, and then this one here corresponds to this branching on one, which is A4.
所以你可以看到这里的这个零对应于这个值四，然后这里的这个对应于一上的分支，即A4。
So we just write it down. Okay. And afterwards, we look at this particular four value again.
所以我们只是写下来。好的。然后，我们再次查看这个特定的四个值。
Left branch is zero, right branch is one. Okay, so now this zero corresponds to this two.
左分支为零，右分支为一。好的，现在这个零对应于这两个。
We write it down. This one here corresponds to this point, which is B2. So we write it down.
我们把它写下来。这里对应的就是这一点，也就是B2。所以我们把它写下来。
Okay, and then finally, from this two, left branch is zero, right branch is one.
好的，最后，从这两个中，左分支为零，右分支为一。
So left branch is D1, okay, one is C1. So we'll be able to write down this particular Huffman code tree already.
所以左边的分支是D1，好吧，一个是C1。所以我们已经能够写下这个特定的霍夫曼代码树了。
So the last step that we need to do is that we need to write down all the code works already.
因此，我们需要做的最后一步是我们需要写下所有已经运行的代码。
So if you want to write down the code work, for example, A, right, for the code work A,
所以如果你想写下代码工作，例如，A，对，对于代码工作A，
we just start off from the root node and trace it until this leaf node here.
我们从根节点开始，一直追踪到这里的叶节点。
The number of bits that it travels through and you collect along the way is your Huffman code work.
它所经过的位数以及您沿途收集的位数就是您的霍夫曼代码工作。
So in other words, if you want to write down the Huffman code work for this number A,
换句话说，如果你想写出这个数字A的霍夫曼编码，
we start from the root node, which is eight, okay, and then we traverse to this leaf node A, right,
我们从根节点开始，就是八，好吧，然后我们遍历到这个叶子节点A，对吧，
the number of bits that you collect along the way is one. So therefore, the Huffman code work for A is one.
您沿途收集的位数为 1。因此，A 的霍夫曼编码工作是一。
Okay, let's just take one more example. Suppose if you want to find what's the Huffman code work for this symbol D, right?
好吧，我们再举一个例子。假设你想找到这个符号 D 的霍夫曼编码是什么，对吗？
So we start from this root node, okay, we want to traverse to this leaf node, so you traverse through this path here.
那么我们就从这个根节点开始，好吧，我们要遍历到这个叶子节点，所以你这里遍历这条路径。
So along the way, the number of bits that you collect is zero, zero, zero.
因此，一路上，您收集的位数为零，零，零。
So therefore, for this symbol D, right, okay, the Huffman code work is zero, zero, zero.
因此，对于这个符号D，对，好吧，霍夫曼编码的工作是零，零，零。
So this is one way for us to generate the Huffman code work set, a very systematic way of doing it.
所以这是我们生成霍夫曼代码工作集的一种方法，一种非常系统的方法。
Okay, and also just now when we look at this particular Huffman code tree here, you can see the root on top,
好的，现在当我们查看这个特定的霍夫曼代码树时，您可以看到顶部的根，
we call it the root node, okay, the branch that, no, the node that has the branching, we call it the branch node, okay.
我们称之为根节点，好吧，分支，不，有分支的节点，我们称之为分支节点，好吧。
The node at the bottom, there's no further branching, we call it the leaf node, okay,
最底部的节点，没有进一步的分支，我们称之为叶节点，好吧，
so that's the definitions of root node, branch node and leaf node.
这就是根节点、分支节点和叶节点的定义。
Okay, so we are going through one simple example of showing how we can create a Huffman code set for this particular example.
好的，我们将通过一个简单的示例来展示如何为这个特定示例创建霍夫曼代码集。
So let's go through a bit more explanation. So this explanation here, just now I already covered earlier.
让我们进一步解释一下。所以这里的解释，刚才我已经讲过了。
So a Huffman code tree is a binary tree with branches assigned a value of zero and one, okay.
因此，霍夫曼码树是一棵二叉树，其分支分配了值 0 和 1，好吧。
It has a tree structure, so the root node is on top, okay, the root of the tree.
它有一个树结构，所以根节点在顶部，好吧，树的根。
The branch node are the nodes that you have the branching, okay, and the leaf node is the termination nodes of the tree, right.
分支节点是有分支的节点，好吧，叶节点是树的终止节点，对吧。
So as seen, this is the root node, these are the branch node and at the bottom, these are the leaf node.
正如所见，这是根节点，这些是分支节点，在底部，这些是叶节点。
Right, so at each branch node, zero and one are assigned to the left and the right branch accordingly, like what we have seen, okay.
是的，所以在每个分支节点，零和一被相应地分配给左分支和右分支，就像我们看到的那样，好吧。
Zero and one, zero and one, zero and one.
零和一，零和一，零和一。
Okay, the code word used for each character or symbol is determined by tracing the path from the root node to the leaf node.
好的，每个字符或符号使用的码字是通过跟踪从根节点到叶节点的路径来确定的。
So the path from the leaf node as you trace traversed from the root node to the leaf node and the number of bits you collect along the way is actually your Huffman code.
因此，当您从根节点跟踪到叶节点时，从叶节点开始的路径以及沿途收集的位数实际上是您的霍夫曼代码。
Right, okay, so that's all is actually a very simple kind of example that we have gone through.
好的，好的，这实际上是我们已经经历过的一个非常简单的例子。
So next, in order to make sure that you fully understand what's the best way, yeah, the best way is for you to do an exercise, right.
那么接下来，为了确保你完全明白什么是最好的方法，是的，最好的方法就是让你做一个练习，对吧。
So actually there are two exercises, okay, and it turned out that later on I find that exercise two is probably a bit easier than exercise one.
所以实际上有两个练习，好吧，后来我发现练习二可能比练习一容易一点。
So therefore we'll probably swap the order a little bit.
因此，我们可能会稍微交换一下顺序。
Let's try to solve this exercise two first, right, and then afterwards we'll come back to exercise one.
让我们先尝试解决练习二，对吧，然后我们再回到练习一。
So let's look at this exercise two.
那么让我们看看这个练习二。
But it states that in the compression scheme, a data source consists of eight symbols with the following probability distribution is given in table one here.
但它指出，在压缩方案中，数据源由八个符号组成，表一给出了以下概率分布。
So in this data source, you have eight symbols, S0 to S1, and these are the probability of occurrences here.
因此，在此数据源中，有八个符号，S0 到 S1，这些是此处出现的概率。
So in part one, it asks you to design a set of Huffman code work set for these eight symbols and clearly show all the steps and calculations involved.
因此，在第一部分中，它要求您为这八个符号设计一套霍夫曼代码工作集，并清楚地显示所涉及的所有步骤和计算。
Right, okay, so yeah, I'll give you a bit of time, right, to try out and then we'll try to go through the answer together.
好吧，好吧，所以是的，我会给你一点时间，好吧，尝试一下，然后我们会一起尝试找到答案。
So I know that the earlier example is a bit simpler because it only involved four symbols and this one is eight symbols.
所以我知道前面的例子更简单一些，因为它只涉及四个符号，而这个是八个符号。
But you should be using the same principle to solve it.
但你应该使用相同的原理来解决它。
So I'll give you a bit of time to think about it, yeah, and then we'll go through the answers together.
所以我会给你一点时间考虑一下，是的，然后我们将一起讨论答案。
What you're looking
你在看什么
Okay, yeah, before you continue, perhaps allow me to play a very short video clip and then perhaps you can tell me what this thing is.
好吧，是的，在你继续之前，也许请允许我播放一个非常短的视频剪辑，然后也许你可以告诉我这东西是什么。
Okay, there's a voice coming out.
好吧，有声音传出来。
Right, do you know, any one of you know what you're watching here?
对了，你们知道吗，你们中有人知道你们在看什么吗？
Yeah, it's actually the neuron growing the connections between two neurons.
是的，它实际上是神经元在两个神经元之间建立连接。
So yeah, I just happened to attend one of the parent-teacher kind of meeting for one of my kids in secondary school.
是的，我只是碰巧参加了我的一个中学孩子的家长会。
So they actually explained to us that if you want your kids to learn effectively, you need to provide opportunity for them to think.
所以他们实际上向我们解释说，如果你想让你的孩子有效地学习，你需要为他们提供思考的机会。
So if you attend any lecture and then if you just listen, usually you'll probably only retain about 30% of the material.
因此，如果您参加任何讲座然后只是听，通常您可能只能记住大约 30% 的材料。
So 100% come in, you keep 30%, 70% of the material will go out.
所以100%进来，你保留30%，70%的材料会出去。
So therefore we need different way to retain this knowledge.
因此，我们需要不同的方式来保留这些知识。
So how you retain this knowledge, right, it can be, for example, by solving some problem like what we are trying to do now, or even writing some books or drawing some pictures when you do the revision.
那么你如何保留这些知识呢，对吧，可以比如说解决一些像我们现在要做的问题，甚至在复习的时候写一些书或者画一些图。
All those activities will help you to strengthen these connections of the sameness, right, to improve your learning effectiveness.
所有这些活动将帮助你加强这些相同的联系，对吧，提高你的学习效率。
Okay, I can see many of you are very eager to solve the problem, so I'll let you continue.
好的，我看到你们很多人都非常渴望解决这个问题，所以我让你们继续。
Okay.
好的。
So at least you have some time to get your brain start working and thinking about it.
所以至少你有一些时间让你的大脑开始工作和思考。
So let's try to go through the key steps that we should do in order to solve the problem.
因此，让我们尝试完成解决问题所应该执行的关键步骤。
So based on the steps that I've described earlier on in the previous example, what's the first thing that you have to do?
因此，根据我之前在上一个示例中描述的步骤，您要做的第一件事是什么？
What's the first thing that you have to do?
你要做的第一件事是什么？
Anyone?
有人吗？
Yeah.
是的。
Okay, we should try to rank all these symbols in the decreasing probability of occurrence and then go through the steps of taking the two lowest probability, try to add them up, and then for the next column, try to rearrange the probability.
好吧，我们应该尝试按照出现概率递减的顺序对所有这些符号进行排序，然后执行取两个最低概率的步骤，尝试将它们相加，然后对于下一列，尝试重新排列概率。
Okay, and after we take the last two probability, add them up, and then try to reorder in the next column.
好的，在我们获取最后两个概率之后，将它们相加，然后尝试在下一列中重新排序。
So you do that repeatedly doing that.
所以你反复这样做。
Okay, so that's a step one.
好的，这是第一步。
And afterwards, what's step two?
然后，第二步是什么？
Step two is you assign the bits on that structure, right?
第二步是分配该结构上的位，对吧？
So the top branch is one, bottom branch is zero.
所以顶部分支是 1，底部分支是 0。
So one, zero, one, zero, one, zero, one, zero.
所以一，零，一，零，一，零，一，零。
So you do the branching.
所以你做分支。
Okay, and then afterwards, what's the step three?
好的，那么第三步是什么？
You construct the Huffman code tree.
您构建霍夫曼代码树。
So you build the Huffman code tree, right, just following the structure.
所以你就按照结构构建了霍夫曼代码树，对吧。
You build the Huffman code tree.
您构建霍夫曼代码树。
And then finally, if you want to determine all the code words, you just trace from the root node all the way to the corresponding leaf node for the symbol.
最后，如果你想确定所有的码字，你只需从根节点一直追踪到符号对应的叶节点即可。
And the number of bits you collect along the way will be your Huffman code tree, I mean the Huffman code word.
你沿途收集的位数将是你的霍夫曼码树，我的意思是霍夫曼码字。
So that's the basic high-level ideas of how we can solve this particular problem using the approach that we have just introduced.
这就是我们如何使用我们刚刚介绍的方法解决这个特定问题的基本高级想法。
So let me try to go through the...
那么让我尝试通过...
Okay.
好的。
All right.
Okay, so this particular solution file, I'm going to upload to the course site afterwards.
好的，这个特定的解决方案文件，我将随后上传到课程网站。
After today's lecture, I'll upload to the course site, so there's no need for you to take pictures or copy.
今天的讲座结束后我会上传到课程网站，所以你不需要拍照或复制。
So afterwards, yeah, latest by tomorrow, you can go and download the solution already.
所以之后，是的，最晚在明天，您就可以去下载解决方案了。
Right, okay, so what we should be paying attention is how do we solve this problem?
好吧，那么我们应该关注的是我们如何解决这个问题呢？
So you can see, if you look at this particular set of symbols with their corresponding probability, as we have mentioned, step one, what we need to do is try to write down these symbols in the decreasing order of probability.
所以你可以看到，如果你看看这组特定的符号及其相应的概率，正如我们在第一步中提到的，我们需要做的就是尝试按概率降序写下这些符号。
In our previous example, it's occurrence.
在我们前面的例子中，它是发生的。
In this particular example, it's a probability.
在这个特定的例子中，它是一个概率。
So probability is a more common cases.
所以概率是比较常见的情况。
So if you look at this set of symbols, you can see S7 has the largest probability and S0 is the smallest.
所以如果你看一下这组符号，你会发现 S7 的概率最大，S0 的概率最小。
So therefore, we need to write down this symbol in the decreasing order of probability.
因此，我们需要按照概率递减的顺序写下这个符号。
Okay, so from 0.26, which is the largest, to 0.02, which is the smallest.
好的，从最大的 0.26 到最小的 0.02。
And afterwards, we take those two symbols with the smallest probability.
然后，我们以最小的概率取这两个符号。
Okay, for example, 0.05 and 0.02, we add them up.
好的，比如说0.05和0.02，我们把它们相加。
So we add them up, we'll notice that it's 0.07.
所以我们将它们相加，我们会发现它是 0.07。
So now, if you compare this 0.07 with respect to all the other probability, you can see it's the smallest.
现在，如果您将这个 0.07 与所有其他概率进行比较，您会发现它是最小的。
So therefore, it needs to be ranked at the bottom and the rest of the probability will just simply transfer over.
因此，它需要排在最后，其余的概率就简单地转移过去。
Okay, so this in your next column.
好的，这在你的下一篇专栏中。
And afterwards, we repeat the exercise. Let me just do it one more time.
然后，我们重复这个练习。让我再做一次。
For example, this 0.08 plus 0.07, that is 0.15.
比如这个0.08加上0.07，那就是0.15。
So once this probability is 0.15, okay, when you move it over to the next column, you can see that 0.15 should be between this 0.16 and 0.14.
因此，一旦这个概率为 0.15，好吧，当您将其移动到下一列时，您可以看到 0.15 应该在 0.16 和 0.14 之间。
So therefore, we need to move it up here, right, the rest of the probability we transfer over.
因此，我们需要把它移到这里，对吧，我们把剩下的概率转移过去。
So for the one that's been replaced, you have to move down here.
所以对于被替换的那个，你必须搬到这里来。
Okay, right, so this is for the next column.
好的，好的，这是下一篇专栏的内容。
So we repeat this exercise. Yeah, so let's just do it one more time.
所以我们重复这个练习。是的，所以我们再做一次吧。
For example, 0.14 plus 0.1 will give you 0.24.
例如，0.14 加 0.1 将得到 0.24。
So 0.24 compared with the other probability, this 0.24 now should be here.
那么0.24与其他概率相比，这个0.24现在应该在这里。
Okay, so 0.26 you move over here and then this 0.19 you move it down.
好的，所以 0.26 你移到这里，然后这个 0.19 你把它移下来。
So that again, this is still in the decreasing order of probability.
因此，这仍然是按概率递减的顺序排列。
So you repeat this particular process, all the, okay, since there are still a few more, let me just continue.
所以你重复这个特定的过程，所有的，好吧，因为还有一些，让我继续。
So 0.16 plus 0.15 now is 0.31, which is the largest as compared to the others.
所以 0.16 加 0.15 现在是 0.31，与其他相比是最大的。
So you need to move the top, the rest you just transfer over, shift it down.
所以你需要移动顶部，其余的你只需转移过来，向下移动。
Okay, and then 0.24 plus 0.19 is 0.43, right, which is the largest now.
好吧，然后0.24加上0.19就是0.43，对吧，现在是最大的了。
So it's 0.43 here, 0.31 and 0.26 you just transfer over, but need to move down.
所以这里是0.43，0.31和0.26你只是转移过去，但需要向下移动。
Okay, and then finally 0.31 plus 0.26 is 0.57, right, which is larger than 0.43.
好的，最后 0.31 加 0.26 就是 0.57，对吧，比 0.43 大。
So you move it up and this you move it down.
所以你把它向上移动，然后你把它向下移动。
So yeah, so the first step is we just simply do the process that we have just described.
是的，第一步我们只是简单地执行我们刚才描述的过程。
And then step two is that you need to assign bits to this branching now.
第二步是您现在需要为该分支分配位。
So for this article course, the kind of convention will be used is that the top branch is V1, bottom branch will be 0.
因此，对于本文课程，将使用的约定是顶部分支为 V1，底部分支为 0。
So it's 1 0, 1 0, 1 0, 1 0, 1 0, 1 0 and 1 0.
所以是 1 0, 1 0, 1 0, 1 0, 1 0, 1 0 和 1 0。
Okay, so that's step two.
好的，这是第二步。
And step three, in order to make it easier for you to trace, right, where the original symbol is,
第三步，为了让你更容易追踪，对，原始符号在哪里，
it's always a good practice that you try to trace this symbol, for example this S7, before it's being merged,
在合并之前尝试跟踪此符号始终是一个好习惯，例如这个 S7，
okay, before it's being combined here.
好吧，在它被合并到这里之前。
So we just write down S7 here.
所以这里就写S7吧。
So this is combined, before it's combined, this is S7.
所以这个组合起来了，组合之前，这是S7。
Okay, so we do the same as well, S6, we follow the path, just before it's being combined is here.
好的，所以我们也做同样的事情，S6，我们沿着这条路走，就在它被组合之前就在这里。
So we write down this S6 here.
所以我们把这款S6写在这里。
So we repeat that for all the other symbols here.
因此，我们对这里的所有其他符号重复这一点。
Then you'll be able to write down the instance of all this symbol before it's being combined.
然后，您将能够在组合之前写下所有这些符号的实例。
So this is to make it easier for you to track, okay, all this symbol.
所以这是为了让你更容易追踪所有这些符号。
So now we have finished this particular, you know, this step already.
所以现在我们已经完成了这个特别的步骤。
And the next thing that we need to do now is that we need to build a Huffman-Coco tree.
我们现在需要做的下一件事是我们需要构建一棵 Huffman-Coco 树。
So the Huffman-Coco tree, you start off with a probability of 1, okay.
所以 Huffman-Coco 树，你从概率 1 开始，好吧。
And the left branch, as we have mentioned in the previous description, left branch is 0, right branch is 1.
而左分支，我们在前面的描述中已经提到，左分支为0，右分支为1。
So these zeros here correspond to this here, 0.43.
所以这里的这些零对应于这里的 0.43。
So we just write down 0.43.
所以我们只写0.43。
And this 1 here corresponding to this branching of 1, okay, is 0.57.
这里的这个1对应于这个1的分支，好吧，是0.57。
Sorry, the resolution is a little bit low, but you can probably still make it up.
抱歉，分辨率有点低，但您仍然可以弥补。
It's 0.57. So we write down 0.57 here.
是0.57。所以我们在这里写下0.57。
So you have done the first branching.
这样你就完成了第一个分支。
So the second branching is actually coming from 0.57.
所以第二个分支实际上来自 0.57。
So therefore the second branching is from 0.57.
因此第二个分支是从 0.57 开始的。
Left branch is 0, right branch is 1.
左分支为0，右分支为1。
So the left branch of 0 corresponds to this branch here.
所以0的左边分支就对应了这里的这个分支。
So it's 0.26S7. So you just write down 0.26S7.
所以是0.26S7。所以你只需写下0.26S7。
And the right branch here is actually 0.31, okay, a bit of 1.
这里的右分支实际上是 0.31，好吧，有点 1。
Okay, so 0.31 here.
好的，这里是 0.31。
Okay, so let's just do it one more time and then the rest you should be quite clear already.
好吧，我们再做一次，剩下的你应该已经很清楚了。
So the next branching is actually 0.43, so which is coming from here.
所以下一个分支实际上是 0.43，所以它来自这里。
Left branch is 0, right branch is 1.
左分支为0，右分支为1。
So this branch of 0 here, okay, corresponds to this 0.19S6 here.
所以这里的这个0分支，好吧，对应这里的这个0.19S6。
So it's 0.19S6.
所以是0.19S6。
Okay, the branch of 1 here corresponds to 0.24.
好的，这里1的分支对应0.24。
So you just write down 0.24.
所以你只需写下 0.24 即可。
So if you repeat the whole process, you will be able to build up your, sorry,
所以，如果你重复整个过程，你将能够建立你的，抱歉，
you will be able to build up your Huffman, you will be able to build up your Huffman code work set here.
您将能够构建您的霍夫曼，您将能够在此处构建您的霍夫曼代码工作集。
Okay, and then next, right, finally, you will be able to build up this Huffman code tree here.
好的，然后接下来，对了，最后，你将能够在这里构建这个霍夫曼代码树。
And then finally, if you want to write down the Huffman code work for each of the symbols,
最后，如果你想写下每个符号的霍夫曼编码，
for example, if we talk about S0, S0 is here.
例如，如果我们谈论S0，S0就在这里。
So as we traverse from the root node through the leaf node, so you can see, right, it's through this branch here.
当我们从根节点遍历叶节点时，你可以看到，对，就是通过这里的这个分支。
The bits that you collect along the way is 1, 1, 0, 0, 0.
您沿途收集的比特是 1, 1, 0, 0, 0。
So therefore this symbol S0 is 1, 1, 0, 0, 0.
因此这个符号 S0 是 1, 1, 0, 0, 0。
Okay, and then let's take one more example.
好吧，那我们再举一个例子。
Suppose S6, if you write down the Huffman code work for S6, you start from the root node, you traverse to the leaf node.
假设S6，如果你写下S6的哈夫曼代码，你从根节点开始，遍历到叶子节点。
The bits you collect along the way is 0, 0.
你一路上收集的比特是 0, 0。
So S6 here, the Huffman code work is 0, 0.
所以这里的S6，哈夫曼码的工作是0, 0。
So therefore by repeating this process, you will be able to write down the Huffman code work set for this particular data distribution.
因此，通过重复此过程，您将能够写下此特定数据分布的霍夫曼代码工作集。
So that is actually the answer to part one.
这实际上是第一部分的答案。
So next let's continue to part two now.
接下来让我们继续第二部分。
So by the way, this is actually one of the past year exam questions.
顺便说一句，这实际上是去年的考试题之一。
So I also mentioned in last week's lecture that I'll try to put in some past year exam questions so that in the class we can go through some of the questions and answers together.
所以我在上周的讲座中也提到，我会尝试放入一些往年的考试题，以便在课堂上我们可以一起复习一些问题和答案。
So you also have some idea about what kind of question will come out in the exam.
因此，您也对考试中会出什么样的问题有所了解。
Also for those discussion questions, you have some idea how to respond to those questions.
另外，对于那些讨论问题，您知道如何回答这些问题。
Okay, so let's continue.
好吧，我们继续吧。
So for part two now, it says that a student originally used eight bits to represent each symbol in an uncompressed scheme.
因此，对于第二部分，它说一名学生最初使用八位来表示未压缩方案中的每个符号。
So you're asked to find the compression ratio of the Huffman coding scheme developed in your part one, when compared with the original uncompressed scheme.
因此，您需要找到第一部分中开发的霍夫曼编码方案与原始未压缩方案相比的压缩率。
So in other words, you're asked to find what is the compression ratio for the Huffman code work set that you have just designed in part one.
换句话说，您需要找出您刚刚在第一部分中设计的霍夫曼代码工作集的压缩比是多少。
Okay, I'll give you a bit of time to think about it and then we'll go through the answers together.
好的，我给你一点时间考虑一下，然后我们一起讨论答案。
Right, so yeah, for those of you who have not obtained the answer for part one, I'll leave it here because you will need it to solve your part two.
是的，是的，对于那些尚未获得第一部分答案的人，我将其留在这里，因为您将需要它来解决第二部分。
Okay.
好的。
Okay, so again, you probably have some time to think about it already.
好吧，再说一遍，你可能已经有时间考虑一下了。
So, okay, any suggestion?
那么，好吧，有什么建议吗？
How do you find the compression ratio for this particular part two?
您如何找到第二部分的压缩比？
Any suggestion?
有什么建议吗？
So if you remember, just now in the earlier part of the lecture, we said that compression ratio is defined as the data storage requirement for an uncompressed data over the data storage requirement for compressed data.
因此，如果您还记得，就在讲座的前面部分，我们说过压缩率被定义为未压缩数据的数据存储要求与压缩数据的数据存储要求之比。
So in this case here, we want to look at a typical, on average, if you are talking about a symbol or a letter, on average, how many bits is required to represent a symbol?
因此，在这种情况下，我们想看看一个典型的，平均而言，如果您正在谈论一个符号或一个字母，平均而言，表示一个符号需要多少位？
Right, if it's uncompressed scheme, uncompressed or the original scheme, how many bits do you need to represent a symbol?
对了，如果是未压缩的方案，未压缩的或者原始的方案，需要多少位来表示一个符号？
According to the question is?
根据问题是？
8 bits, right?
8 位，对吗？
So therefore, the storage requirement to represent for the uncompressed scheme is actually 8 bits per symbol.
因此，表示未压缩方案的存储要求实际上是每个符号 8 位。
Okay, now the next question is that what is the average number of bits that is required to represent a symbol for this compressed scheme?
好的，现在下一个问题是表示此压缩方案的符号所需的平均位数是多少？
In other words, for this Huffman code work set that you have designed just now, what is the average number of bits that is required to represent a symbol?
换句话说，对于您刚刚设计的这个霍夫曼代码工作集，表示一个符号所需的平均位数是多少？
So we have just now designed our Huffman code work set already.
所以我们刚刚已经设计了我们的霍夫曼代码工作集。
What is the average number of bits that is required to represent this symbol using this Huffman code work set?
使用此霍夫曼代码工作集表示此符号所需的平均位数是多少？
How do we do that?
我们该怎么做呢？
Okay, so but the approach is that you need to find the expected number of bits per symbol, right?
好的，但是方法是您需要找到每个符号的预期位数，对吧？
So which would then be, how do you find the expected number of bits required to represent the symbol?
那么，如何找到表示该符号所需的预期位数呢？
Is the probability multiplied with the number of bits, right, for the particular symbol, the probability of the symbol multiplied with the number of bits required to represent the symbol, and you sum up over all the symbols.
是概率乘以位数，对吧，对于特定符号，符号的概率乘以表示该符号所需的位数，然后对所有符号求和。
So in other words, if you look at it, okay, for this S2, the probability that you occur is 0.02.
那么也就是说，你看一下，好吧，对于这个S2，你出现的概率是0.02。
And how many bits is required to represent this S0? For S0, the probability is actually 0.02.
而表示这个S0需要多少位呢？对于 S0，概率实际上是 0.02。
So how many bits is required to represent this S0 based on what we have designed?
那么根据我们的设计，需要多少位来表示这个S0呢？
It's actually 5 bits.
实际上是5位。
So therefore, the probability now is actually 0.02 multiplied with these 5 bits, yeah, plus, okay, what is the probability, if you choose any symbol, what is the probability that it will be S1?
所以，现在的概率实际上是 0.02 乘以这 5 位，是的，加上，好吧，概率是多少，如果你选择任何符号，它是 S1 的概率是多少？
It will be 0.05. And if it's S1, what is the number of bits that is required to represent it?
它将是 0.05。如果是 S1，表示它需要多少位？
It's actually 5 bits, huh?
它实际上是 5 位，是吗？
Okay, so, and then if you choose a symbol randomly, what is the probability that it will be S2 ASB?
好的，那么，如果你随机选择一个符号，它是 S2 ASB 的概率是多少？
It's actually 0.08. And with 0.08, how many bits is required to represent it?
实际上是0.08。那么0.08需要多少位来表示呢？
It's actually 4 bits, huh?
它实际上是 4 位，是吗？
So therefore, you can see pretty much it's like this. You ask the question, if you choose a symbol randomly, what is the probability that it will belong to each of these particular symbols?
因此，你可以看到几乎是这样的。你问一个问题，如果你随机选择一个符号，它属于每个特定符号的概率是多少？
Okay, and then you need to multiply with the corresponding number of bits to represent the symbol and then add them up.
好吧，然后你需要乘以相应的位数来表示符号，然后将它们相加。
That's pretty much the answer.
这几乎就是答案。
Okay, so therefore, let's try to go through this part two.
好的，那么，让我们尝试完成第二部分。
So part two, you can see, first we need to calculate the average number of bits that is used to represent the symbol.
所以第二部分，你可以看到，首先我们需要计算用于表示符号的平均位数。
So as I mentioned, to do this calculation, we ask ourselves, if we choose a symbol randomly, what is the chances it will be a symbol S0?
正如我提到的，为了进行此计算，我们问自己，如果我们随机选择一个符号，它是符号 S0 的机会有多大？
Okay, so the probability is 0.02. And if it's S0, the number of bits that is required to represent it is 5 bits.
好的，所以概率是 0.02。如果是S0，则表示它所需的位数是5位。
Okay, and afterwards, if you choose a symbol randomly, what is the chances it will be S1?
好的，然后，如果你随机选择一个符号，它是 S1 的几率是多少？
So it's actually 0.05. And if it's S1, then the number of bits that is required to represent it is 5 bits.
所以实际上是0.05。如果是S1，则表示它所需的位数是5位。
Okay, and then, yeah, and then so on and so forth.
好吧，然后，是的，然后等等。
Let me just do one more. If you choose a symbol randomly, what are the chances it will belong to S2?
让我再做一件事。如果你随机选择一个符号，它属于 S2 的机会有多大？
So it's 0.08. So if it's 0.08, how many bits is required to represent it? It's 4 bits, so you multiply by 4.
所以是0.08。那么如果是0.08，需要多少位来表示呢？它是 4 位，所以乘以 4。
So you continue for all the symbols, and afterwards, at the end, you'll see that it's 2.77 bits per symbol.
因此，您继续处理所有符号，然后在最后，您将看到每个符号 2.77 位。
So on average, that means on average, you require 2.77 bits to represent a symbol.
因此，平均而言，这意味着平均需要 2.77 位来表示一个符号。
Okay, so now, as explained earlier on, from this question, it still tells you that for uncompressed scheme,
好的，现在，正如前面所解释的，从这个问题，它仍然告诉你对于未压缩的方案，
you will be using 8 bits to represent a symbol. Now, if you use our Huffman code work set that we've designed,
您将使用 8 位来表示一个符号。现在，如果您使用我们设计的霍夫曼代码工作集，
the number of bits to represent, I don't know why, is 2.77 bits per symbol.
我不知道为什么，要表示的位数是每个符号 2.77 位。
So therefore, the compression ratio is a storage requirement for uncompressed data over the compressed data.
因此，压缩率是未压缩数据相对于压缩数据的存储要求。
So if you do some calculation, you'll see that it's 2.888. So this is the compression ratio for this scheme.
因此，如果您进行一些计算，您会发现它是 2.888。这就是该方案的压缩比。
That means you're actually almost able to achieve a compression ratio of every 2.88 bits, you can compress it into 1 bit, yeah?
这意味着你实际上几乎能够实现每 2.88 位的压缩比，你可以将其压缩为 1 位，是吗？
Okay, which is pretty good. So next, let's look at the last question.
好的，这非常好。那么接下来我们看最后一个问题。
So last question, it asks you to find the entropy of this data source,
所以最后一个问题，它要求你找到这个数据源的熵，
and briefly discuss whether it's possible to design a Huffman code work set which can achieve a target of less than 2.5 bits per symbol.
并简要讨论是否有可能设计一个霍夫曼编码工作集来实现每个符号小于 2.5 位的目标。
Okay, right, so we have just learned about the entropy for a data set. Let's try to calculate using the formula.
好吧，我们刚刚了解了数据集的熵。让我们尝试使用公式计算一下。
You can do a bit of calculation, and afterwards, based on your result, try to answer the question,
你可以做一些计算，然后根据你的结果尝试回答这个问题，
can we ever achieve a target of less than 2.5 bits per symbol?
我们能否实现每个符号少于 2.5 位的目标？
Again, I'll give you a bit of time to think about it, and we'll go through the answers together.
再次，我会给你一些时间来思考这个问题，我们将一起讨论答案。
Okay.
好的。
Okay, so yeah, at least you have some time to think about it.
好吧，是的，至少你有时间考虑一下。
Any suggestion? How do we find the entropy of this data source?
有什么建议吗？我们如何找到这个数据源的熵？
Just apply a formula that we have learned earlier on, right?
只要应用我们之前学过的公式就可以了，对吧？
Okay, so I think that part should be quite straightforward. Okay, so let's go ahead and do it.
好的，所以我认为这部分应该非常简单。好吧，让我们继续吧。
Right, okay, so therefore the answer to that part is that we just applied this formula that we have mentioned earlier on.
好吧，所以这部分的答案是我们刚刚应用了前面提到的这个公式。
So the probability Pi, log Pi with a base of 2, you sum up over all the possible symbols in this data set,
所以概率 Pi，以 2 为底的 log Pi，您可以总结该数据集中所有可能的符号，
and you put a negative sign in front.
然后你在前面加上一个负号。
Okay, so therefore for this particular question, you can see the first term is actually 0.02.
好的，因此对于这个特定问题，您可以看到第一项实际上是 0.02。
So 0.02, log 0.02 to the base of 2, right, add up, second term is 0.05, log 0.05, and then you repeat for all the symbols.
所以 0.02，对数 0.02 以 2 为底，对，相加，第二项是 0.05，对数 0.05，然后对所有符号重复。
Okay, you add all of them up, and finally you put a negative sign in front of it.
好吧，你把它们全部加起来，最后在前面加上一个负号。
So if you're not so familiar with using the calculator to do it, yeah, probably it's a good time for you to familiarize yourself how to do some logarithm with base 2.
因此，如果您不太熟悉如何使用计算器来执行此操作，那么现在可能是您熟悉如何计算以 2 为底的对数的好时机。
Or you can actually also use some simple mathematics to convert it into base 10 as well.
或者您实际上也可以使用一些简单的数学将其转换为基数 10。
So anyway, either way, just do the calculation, you see that it's 2.733 bits per symbol.
所以无论如何，无论哪种方式，只要进行计算，您就会看到每个符号 2.733 位。
So then with that particular answer, now we need to answer the last question, which is,
那么有了这个特定的答案，现在我们需要回答最后一个问题，即
discuss whether it's possible to design a half-moon cobalt set that can achieve the target of less than 2.5 bits per symbol.
讨论是否有可能设计一个半月钴组来实现每个符号少于 2.5 位的目标。
So is it possible to do that?
那么可以这样做吗？
Is it possible?
是否可以？
No, huh?
不，是吧？
So earlier on, if you remember what we discussed, right, so entropy actually is the smallest value that you need, right, in order to,
所以之前，如果你还记得我们讨论过的内容，那么熵实际上是你需要的最小值，对吧，为了，
the smallest number of bits that you need to represent a symbol, right, so theoretically it's a theoretical lower bound, you cannot go anything below it.
表示一个符号所需的最小位数，对，所以理论上它是一个理论上的下限，你不能低于它。
You can use more bits to represent each symbol, but you cannot use less bit than this entropy.
您可以使用更多的位来表示每个符号，但不能使用比该熵更少的位。
So since entropy is already 2.73, you cannot get any value less than that, okay.
因为熵已经是 2.73，所以你不能得到任何小于这个值的值，好吧。
So therefore, the answer to that part is that as the target of 2.5 bits per symbol is less than the entropy,
因此，该部分的答案是，由于每个符号 2.5 位的目标小于熵，
it's not possible to design a half-moon cobalt set that can meet this target, right.
不可能设计出能够达到这个目标的半月形钴组，对吧。
So that's the answer to this question.
这就是这个问题的答案。
So as I mentioned, the answer to this question, I will upload to the course site and then I'll release it by tomorrow.
正如我提到的，这个问题的答案，我将上传到课程网站，然后在明天之前发布。
So tomorrow on works, you can go and download it, okay.
那么明天上班你就可以去下载了，好吧。
So that's the answer to question one.
这就是问题一的答案。
So let's move on to question two.
那么让我们继续讨论第二个问题。
Right, okay, so today we start out with two pretty lengthy exercises, right, so let's try to do it,
好吧，好吧，所以今天我们从两个相当长的练习开始，好吧，所以让我们尝试一下，
because sometimes it's easier for you to learn through exercise rather than just reading.
因为有时通过练习比仅仅阅读更容易学习。
So let's look at these questions here.
那么让我们在这里看看这些问题。
It says that in a compression scheme, eight symbols are used to represent different patterns in the information source, right.
它说在压缩方案中，使用八个符号来表示信息源中的不同模式，对吧。
The symbols are encoded using this particular code, codebook A.
这些符号使用这个特定的代码（码本 A）进行编码。
So codebook A and the probability of occurrence is given in this table, whereas m and n are positive real value.
因此，该表中给出了码本A和出现的概率，而m和n是正实值。
So you have this particular set that consists of eight symbols, s0 to s7, right.
所以你有这个特殊的集合，它由八个符号组成，s0 到 s7，对吧。
So these are probability of occurrence, okay, m and n, we do not know their value yet, okay.
所以这些是发生的概率，好吧，m 和 n，我们还不知道它们的值，好吧。
And we also have a particular codebook A.
我们还有一个特定的密码本 A。
So someone has come up with this particular codebook A, and this is the codebook A here, right.
所以有人想出了这个特殊的码本A，这就是这里的码本A，对吧。
So now let's look at the first question.
那么现在我们来看看第一个问题。
So the first question is that in the first scenario, if the average number of bits per symbol for the compression scheme
所以第一个问题是，在第一种情况下，如果压缩方案的每个符号的平均位数
need to be less than 2.86, right, find the required condition for this value m and n, right.
需要小于2.86，对吧，找到这个值m和n所需要的条件，对吧。
So I think the question is quite straightforward, okay.
所以我认为这个问题很简单，好吧。
You have this particular, this set has eight symbols.
你有这个特殊的，这个集合有八个符号。
These are the probability of occurrence, and m and n are known, right.
这些是发生的概率，m和n是已知的，对吧。
This is, someone has already designed this codebook set here, right, we call it codebook A, right.
这是，这里已经有人设计好了这套码本，对吧，我们称之为码本A，对吧。
And you are told that for this codebook A, right, the number of, if the average number of bits per symbol
你被告知，对于这个码本 A，对，如果每个符号的平均位数
need to be less than this value, what should be the condition that this m and n need to satisfy?
需要小于这个值，这个m和n需要满足什么条件呢？
Right, okay, so again, I'll give you a bit of time to think about it, and then we'll go through the answers together.
好吧，好吧，我再给你一点时间考虑一下，然后我们一起看一下答案。
Okay.
好的。
Yeah, again, I hope that you have some time to think about this question.
是的，我再次希望你有时间思考这个问题。
Right, okay, so yeah, in order to find out the condition, so what do we need to do?
对啊，好吧，所以是啊，为了找出状况，那么我们需要做什么呢？
So we need to establish some inequality, right.
所以我们需要建立一些不平等，对吧。
So first of all, how do we find out an expression, right, for the average number of bits that's required to represent a symbol for this scheme here?
首先，我们如何找到一个表达式，对吧，代表这个方案的符号所需的平均位数？
How do you find out the average number of bits that's required to represent a symbol in terms of m and n here?
你如何找出用 m 和 n 表示一个符号所需的平均位数？
What do we have to do?
我们必须做什么？
We take m multiplied, okay, so again, we use the same argument like the previous question.
我们将 m 相乘，好吧，我们再次使用与上一个问题相同的参数。
If you choose a symbol randomly, what is the chances it will be s0?
如果你随机选择一个符号，它是 s0 的几率是多少？
It will be m, right?
会是m，对吗？
m is m, how many bits do you require to represent?
m是m，需要多少位来表示？
Two bits, so it's m times 2.
两位，所以是 m 乘以 2。
Plus, if you choose a symbol randomly, what's the chances it's s1?
另外，如果你随机选择一个符号，它是 s1 的几率是多少？
It's n, huh?
是n吧？
If it's n, how many bits do you require to represent it?
如果是n，需要多少位来表示？
Three bits, so it's three times n, right?
三位，所以是 n 的三倍，对吗？
Okay, and what is the, choose a symbol randomly, what's the chances it will be s2?
好吧，那是什么，随机选择一个符号，它是 s2 的几率是多少？
It will be 0.15, m is 0.15, for s2, how many bits do you require to represent it?
它将是0.15，m是0.15，对于s2，你需要多少位来表示它？
It's three bits, so you just actually do that, right?
它是三位，所以你实际上就这么做了，对吧？
You just take a probability, multiply with the number of bits, and you sum up over all the possible combination,
你只需计算一个概率，乘以位数，然后对所有可能的组合求和，
but that is the average number of bits that is required to represent a symbol.
但这是表示一个符号所需的平均位数。
Okay, so, and you know that the average number of bits that is required to represent a symbol
好的，你知道表示一个符号所需的平均位数
need to be less than 2.86, so therefore, you will have your first inequality.
需要小于 2.86，因此，您将得到第一个不等式。
Actually, I don't want to show so quickly.
其实我不想这么快表现出来。
Yeah, so you can see, right, m times 2 bits plus n times 3 bits plus 0.5 times 3 bits and so on and so forth,
是的，所以你可以看到，对，m 乘以 2 位加上 n 乘以 3 位加上 0.5 乘以 3 位，依此类推，
you add up over all of them.
你把它们全部加起来。
If you have done that at the end, okay, it will be this particular expression.
如果你最后这样做了，好吧，这将是这个特定的表达。
It will be this particular expression.
这将是这个特定的表达。
And we know that this is an average number of bits for a symbol,
我们知道这是一个符号的平均位数，
and from the question you are told that this number needs to be less than 2.86,
从问题中得知这个数字必须小于 2.86，
so this number needs to be less than 2.86, right?
所以这个数字必须小于 2.86，对吧？
If you do some simplification, you can see then 2m plus 3m needs to be less than 1.41.
如果进行一些简化，您会发现 2m 加 3m 需要小于 1.41。
So that is the first inequality.
这就是第一个不等式。
So are there any other conditions that you can impose for this question, for m and n?
那么对于这个问题，对于 m 和 n 是否还有其他条件可以强加？
Any other condition?
还有什么条件吗？
Yeah, so the sum of all the probability must be equal to 1, right?
是的，所以所有概率的总和一定等于 1，对吗？
So therefore, what it means is that if you sum up all this probability, it should be equal to 1.
因此，这意味着如果将所有这些概率相加，它应该等于 1。
Then afterwards, you can obtain your second condition.
然后，你就可以得到你的第二个条件了。
So with that in mind, knowing that sum of probability should be equal to 1, okay?
考虑到这一点，概率之和应该等于 1，好吗？
So we just add up all this probability here.
所以我们在这里将所有这些概率相加。
You can see it's equal to 1. We simplify a little bit.
你可以看到它等于1。我们稍微简化一下。
We see that m plus n is 0.54, or you can write n is equal to 0.54 minus n.
我们看到m加n是0.54，或者你可以写n等于0.54减n。
So you have one inequality and one equality.
因此，存在一种不平等和一种平等。
So afterwards, you substitute this 2 into 1.
所以之后，你把这个2代入1。
I think most of you should be familiar with this.
我想你们大多数人都应该熟悉这一点。
So if you simplify a little bit, you can see that you can derive the condition m needs to be greater than 0.21.
因此，如果稍微简化一下，您可以看到可以推导出条件 m 需要大于 0.21。
And then likewise, if you simplify a little bit further, you put this condition into, put this thing into here,
然后同样地，如果你进一步简化一点，你把这个条件放进去，把这个东西放进去，
simplify a little bit, you'll be able to see n will be between 0 and 0.33.
稍微简化一下，您将能够看到 n 将在 0 到 0.33 之间。
So this is how you can find the condition that m and n need to satisfy for this question.
这就是如何找到本题 m 和 n 需要满足的条件。
So let's continue.
那么让我们继续吧。
So next it says that in the second scenario, in the second case now, if the value of m is 0.3, n is 0.24,
那么接下来它说在第二种情况下，现在第二种情况下，如果m的值为0.3，n为0.24，
discuss the effectiveness of code work A in encoding the symbol to achieve compression.
讨论代码工作 A 对符号进行编码以实现压缩的有效性。
And then afterwards, they ask you to compare code work A and Huffman coding and discuss whether code work A is optimal
然后他们让你比较代码工作A和霍夫曼编码并讨论代码工作A是否是最优的
in terms of performing the compression.
在执行压缩方面。
So let's look at the first part first.
那么我们先看第一部分。
They say if the value m is 0.3, n is 0.24, discuss whether code work A is effective in performing the compression.
他们说如果值 m 为 0.3，n 为 0.24，则讨论代码工作 A 在执行压缩时是否有效。
And if you have a quick look, if m is 0.3, this is 0.24, and this code work A is, this is the pattern here.
如果你快速看一下，如果 m 是 0.3，则这是 0.24，并且此代码工作 A 是，这就是这里的模式。
So based on the principles of entropy encoding, does it seems reasonable?
那么基于熵编码的原理，看起来合理吗？
So if this is 0.3, this is 0.2, you can see this is actually in decreasing probability.
所以如果这是 0.3，这是 0.2，你可以看到这实际上是概率递减。
And also if you observe the number of bits, right, for those symbols with larger probability, the number of bit is actually less.
而且如果你观察比特数，对吧，对于那些概率较大的符号，比特数实际上更少。
Those with the smallest probability, the number of bit is larger.
概率最小的，位数较大。
So therefore, from the principles of entropy encoding or variable length coding, it seems reasonable.
因此，从熵编码或变长编码的原理来看，似乎是合理的。
It seems reasonable.
看来有道理。
It's consistent with our understanding of how variable length coding should work.
这与我们对可变长度编码如何工作的理解是一致的。
But now, okay, the next one is they ask you to compare code book A with Huffman coding.
但现在，好吧，下一个是他们要求你将代码书 A 与霍夫曼编码进行比较。
And then afterwards decide whether this code book A is optimal, whether it's the best.
然后再判断这个码本A是否是最优的，是否是最好的。
So this will require you to do some calculation.
所以这需要你做一些计算。
So I'll give you some time to think about it or to do your calculation.
所以我会给你一些时间去思考或者做你的计算。
And then we'll go through this last part together.
然后我们将一起完成最后一部分。
So this is Huffman.
这就是霍夫曼。
Yes.
是的。
Can we answer the question a bit later?
我们可以稍后回答这个问题吗？
Sorry?
对不起？
Yeah, yeah.
是啊是啊。
Okay.
好的。
Yes, you see this.
是的，你看到了这个。
Okay, so any suggestion
好的，所以有什么建议吗
on how we can do this part B?
我们如何才能完成这 B 部分？
You want to compare this
你想比较这个
codebook A and the Huffman coding,
码本 A 和霍夫曼编码，
whether this codebook A
该码本是否为A
is optimal or not, what should we do?
是最优还是不是最优，我们该怎么办？
So first of all, we need to...
所以首先，我们需要...
Sorry?
对不起？
Yeah, okay, so we need to go through the process
是的，好的，所以我们需要完成这个过程
of building the Huffman codebook set
构建霍夫曼密码本集
and afterwards, suppose once you have done that,
之后，假设一旦你这样做了，
once you have done that, what should we do?
一旦你这样做了，我们应该做什么？
What should we do?
我们应该做什么？
Calculate the average number of bits per symbol
计算每个符号的平均位数
that's required for Huffman codebook set, right?
这是霍夫曼密码本集所必需的，对吧？
And afterwards you compare which one is larger, right?
然后你比较一下哪个更大，对吗？
So if, for example, your Huffman
例如，如果你的霍夫曼
codebook set can represent the symbol
码本集可以表示符号
with a smaller number of bits per symbol,
每个符号的位数较少，
then that means your codebook A is not optimal already.
那么这意味着你的密码本 A 还不是最佳的。
So that's pretty much the plan.
这就是计划。
So that's what we need to do.
这就是我们需要做的。
So in order to do that, we need to go through the process.
因此，为了做到这一点，我们需要完成这个过程。
So this process I will not
所以这个过程我不会
go through too much in detail.
经历太多细节。
But anyway, from the earlier part,
但无论如何，从前面的部分来看，
we say that in order to see
我们说是为了看到
whether, for example, codebook A, whether it's reasonable
例如，密码本A是否合理
from the entropy coding perspective,
从熵编码的角度来看，
so we can see that from the probability of occurrence,
所以从发生的概率我们可以看出，
larger probability corresponds to shorter codebook.
较大的概率对应于较短的码本。
This is the idea of entropy coding.
这就是熵编码的思想。
So early on, you will see this is point three and this is point two,
所以很早就，你会看到这是第三点，这是第二点，
just like we mentioned here.
就像我们在这里提到的那样。
Larger probability is shorter codebook, smaller probability larger codebook.
概率越大，码本越短，概率越小，码本越大。
So therefore, this is actually consistent
因此，这实际上是一致的
with the idea of entropy coding.
结合熵编码的思想。
So now, however, to check whether this codebook A is optimal,
然而，现在要检查这个密码本 A 是否是最佳的，
we need to actually derive this Huffman codebook set.
我们需要实际导出这个霍夫曼码本集。
So we go through this particular motion,
所以我们通过这个特殊的动议，
this process that I mentioned to you before.
我之前向你提到过这个过程。
So we try to rank this particular symbol
所以我们尝试对这个特定的符号进行排名
in decreasing order of probability.
按概率降序排列。
And then for the two smallest probability, we add them up.
然后对于两个最小的概率，我们将它们相加。
And then we move it to the next column
然后我们将其移动到下一列
by rearranging the probability.
通过重新排列概率。
So this is point seven, it should be here.
这是第七点，应该在这里。
The rest just transfer over.
剩下的就转移过去吧。
So we repeat that particular process,
所以我们重复这个特定的过程，
we'll be able to draw these particular structures here.
我们将能够在这里绘制这些特定的结构。
So that's step one.
这是第一步。
Step two is that we assign the bits, top branch is one, bottom branch is zero.
第二步是我们分配位，顶部分支是 1，底部分支是 0。
One zero, one zero, one zero. So that's step two.
一零，一零，一零。这是第二步。
Step three is that we transfer this particular symbol
第三步是我们转移这个特定的符号
just before it's being merged for easy tracking.
就在它被合并以便于跟踪之前。
So this is zero, this is S1.
所以这是零，这是 S1。
So for easy tracking when you want to draw the Huffman code tree.
这样便于在绘制哈夫曼码树时方便跟踪。
So suppose we go through this particular process.
假设我们经历这个特定的过程。
Let's continue this one, we can skip for one moment.
让我们继续这一节，我们可以暂时跳过。
So based on this particular structure,
所以基于这个特殊的结构，
then we can build our Huffman code tree.
然后我们就可以构建我们的霍夫曼代码树。
So let's assume that you can go home and try it out yourself.
因此，我们假设您可以回家亲自尝试一下。
You will see that this is the Huffman code tree
你会看到这是霍夫曼码树
that you'll be able to construct.
你将能够构建。
And then finally, if you want to find out what is the Huffman code work for each of the symbols,
最后，如果您想了解每个符号的霍夫曼编码是什么，
for example for S0 which is somewhere here,
例如对于位于此处某处的 S0，
the code work should be 1, 1.
代码工作应该是 1, 1。
If you take one example which is S7,
如果以S7为例，
which is here, as you can see from this root node,
正如您从根节点中看到的那样，
is 1, 0, 0, 1, 0.
是 1, 0, 0, 1, 0。
So S7 is 1, 0, 0, 1, 0 here.
所以这里S7就是1,0,0,1,0。
So you'll be able to write down all the code works
这样你就可以写下所有代码的工作原理
that you want to construct.
你想要构建的。
So you'll be able to write down all the code work
这样你就可以写下所有的代码工作
for this particular Huffman coding here.
对于这个特定的霍夫曼编码在这里。
So once you have built up this particular Huffman code work set here,
因此，一旦您在这里建立了这个特定的霍夫曼代码工作集，
you can go through the process that we have mentioned a couple of times already.
您可以完成我们已经提到过几次的过程。
We can calculate the average number of bits per symbol for this Huffman code work set.
我们可以计算该霍夫曼代码工作集每个符号的平均位数。
So if you do that, you can see,
所以如果你这样做，你会看到，
so the probability that it will be this symbol S0 is 0.3,
所以这个符号 S0 的概率是 0.3，
and it's 2 bits.
它是 2 位。
If it's the probability it will be S1 is 0.24 from the question,
如果问题中 S1 的概率为 0.24，
and it's 2 bits.
它是 2 位。
So if you do that, you do the calculation,
所以如果你这样做，你就会进行计算，
you'll see that it's 2.66 bits per symbol.
您会看到每个符号为 2.66 位。
This is if you use the Huffman code work set that you just derived.
这是如果您使用刚刚导出的霍夫曼代码工作集的话。
So on the other hand, if you use just now the code book A,
那么另一方面，如果你使用刚才的码本A，
so this is the code book A,
所以这是密码书A，
so the code book A, the number of bits per symbol that we have,
所以码书 A，我们拥有的每个符号的位数，
if you choose this particular symbol S0,
如果你选择这个特定的符号S0，
it's actually 0.3, and it's 2 bits.
它实际上是 0.3，并且是 2 位。
If you choose that the symbol randomly is S1,
如果随机选择符号为S1，
the probability is actually 0.24 from the question,
从问题来看，概率实际上是 0.24，
and it's 0.24, and the number of bits that is required is 3 bits.
是0.24，需要的位数是3位。
So if you choose the symbol S2, the probability is 0.15,
所以如果你选择符号S2，概率是0.15，
and for code book A, it's actually 3 bits.
对于码书A来说，它实际上是3位。
So therefore, for code book A,
因此，对于码本 A，
if you calculate the average number of bits per symbol,
如果计算每个符号的平均位数，
if you go through the process and you do the calculation,
如果你完成这个过程并进行计算，
you'll see it's 2.77 bits per symbol.
您会看到每个符号 2.77 位。
So on the other hand, if you go through the process,
所以另一方面 如果你经历了这个过程
you build your Huffman code work set,
您构建霍夫曼代码工作集，
if you do the calculation, you'll see you only require 2.66 bits per symbol.
如果您进行计算，您会发现每个符号只需要 2.66 位。
Therefore, using your Huffman code work set is actually more effective
因此，使用霍夫曼代码工作集实际上更有效
and more efficient.
并且更加高效。
So therefore, from that particular perspective,
因此，从这个特定的角度来看，
we can say that this code book A is not optimal in terms of performing the compression,
我们可以说这个码本 A 在执行压缩方面并不是最佳的，
because at least the Huffman code work set that you've designed
因为至少您设计的霍夫曼代码工作集
is more effective in terms of compression as compared to code book A.
与码书A相比，在压缩方面更有效。
So therefore, you can see that code book A requires 2.77 bits per symbol,
因此，您可以看到码本 A 每个符号需要 2.77 位，
which is greater than 2.66 bits per symbol by Huffman coding.
通过霍夫曼编码，每个符号大于 2.66 位。
So therefore, we can conclude that code book A is actually not optimal.
因此，我们可以得出结论，码书A实际上不是最优的。
Even though at first glance it looks like it's actually good,
虽然乍一看确实不错
because it's consistent with your entropy coding principle,
因为它符合你的熵编码原理，
but if you do some closer examination,
但如果你仔细检查一下
if you compare to Huffman coding, which is usually the benchmark,
如果与通常作为基准的霍夫曼编码进行比较，
you can see that your Huffman coding is actually more efficient.
你可以看到你的霍夫曼编码实际上更有效。
So therefore, your code book A is not the optimal choice.
因此，您的密码本 A 不是最佳选择。
So this is the answer to this exercise.
这就是本练习的答案。
So as I mentioned, both exercises I'll upload to the course site after tomorrow,
正如我提到的，这两个练习我都会在明天之后上传到课程网站，
so you can go and download it.
所以你可以去下载它。
So we spent quite a fair bit of time going through these two exercises,
所以我们花了相当多的时间来完成这两个练习，
and hopefully you have a better understanding about this entropy and coding
希望您对这种熵和编码有更好的理解
and Huffman coding process already.
和霍夫曼编码过程已经。
We'll take a short break.
我们会短暂休息一下。
Now it's 8.02.
现在是8.02。
So probably let's come back at 8.20.
所以我们可能会在 8.20 回来。
Ah.
啊。
So you're not saying that the probability is not M?
所以你不是说概率不是M？
No, no.
不，不。
There's no need to say that the probability is not M.
不用说概率不是M。
Just that I wanted to make it easier for students.
只是我想让学生更容易。
In the exam, I intentionally increased the probability of the answer.
考试时，我故意增加了答对的概率。
But I don't necessarily say that the probability is not M.
但我不一定说概率不是M。
Okay, okay.
好吧，好吧。
That's it.
就是这样。
Could you show me the X is one in first scenario?
你能告诉我 X 是第一个场景中的一个吗？
One limitation is 2M plus 3M is less than 1.41.
一个限制是 2M 加 3M 小于 1.41。
How is the second limitation?
第二个限制如何？
Okay, because this is a probability,
好吧，因为这是一个概率，
so all the probability add up must be equal to 1.
所以所有的概率加起来一定等于 1。
Okay, I got it.
好的，我明白了。
Thank you.
谢谢。
So this is the first one.
这是第一个。
If this is a big or small table,
如果这是一张大桌子或小桌子，
should we keep a N?
我们应该保留一个N吗？
Actually, this question is the same as what the student said earlier.
其实这个问题和刚才那位同学说的是一样的。
In fact, it doesn't say that the probability is not M.
其实并没有说概率不是M。
Just that the other symbols,
只是其他的符号，
the probability is all 8 to 5.
概率都是8到5。
These two are actually M.
这两个其实都是M。
So actually, N can be a big or small table.
所以实际上，N 可以是一个大表或一个小表。
This is basically the Hafen rule.
这基本上就是哈芬规则。
Hafen rule itself is a rule.
哈芬规则本身就是一个规则。
These are the processes we analyzed earlier.
这些是我们之前分析的过程。
In fact, people have already analyzed it.
其实人们已经分析过了。
This is a rule.
这是一条规则。
So it can't be more than, or more than 1M?
那么不能超过，或者超过1M？
Actually, in the Hafen rule,
事实上，在哈芬规则中，
it is possible that there is a condition of 0 and 1.
可能存在0和1的条件。
But this question, because of its probability distribution,
但是这个问题，由于它的概率分布，
the probability distribution causes this Hafen rule,
概率分布导致了这个 Hafen 规则，
which is the smallest, the biggest opportunity for the symbol to be a 0.
这是符号成为 0 的最小、最大的机会。
What I want to say is,
我想说的是，
if your question is,
如果你的问题是
is it possible that there are some symbols in the Hafen rule,
哈芬规则中是否有可能存在一些符号，
just one 0 or something?
只是一个 0 或者什么？
It is possible.
这是可能的。
But this question, because of its probability distribution,
但是这个问题，由于它的概率分布，
the shortest Hafen rule is not a 0 or something.
最短的 Hafen 规则不是 0 或其他值。
But this 0 cannot be a 0?
但是这个0不可能是0吧？
This is a probability distribution.
这是一个概率分布。
Because according to its probability distribution,
因为根据其概率分布，
and the description process,
以及描述过程，
it is a systemized,
它是一个系统化的、
a small, half-or-half rule.
一个小的、一半或一半的规则。
This is a standard rule.
这是一个标准规则。
So this is a 1?
所以这是一个1？
The above 1 is a type of 1.
上面的1是1的类型。
This is the question.
这就是问题所在。
This question is calculated by the length of the smallest average
这题是通过最小平均长度来计算的
and the length of the code.
以及代码的长度。
Can it reach 2.5G?
能达到2.5G吗？
No, it cannot.
不，不能。
This is the second question.
这是第二个问题。
It is the last question.
这是最后一个问题。
It is called entropy.
它被称为熵。
Entropy is the smallest theory.
熵是最小的理论。
But in many cases,
但在很多情况下，
you cannot find the lower bound.
你找不到下限。
So generally, we will not...
所以一般情况下我们不会...
If you say you want to force it,
如果你说你想强迫的话
you will know immediately by using entropy.
使用熵你会立即知道。
No, it is not possible.
不，这是不可能的。
Because entropy is the smallest of the theories.
因为熵是最小的理论。
So if you want to be smaller than this value,
所以如果你想小于这个值，
entropy can tell you.
熵可以告诉你。
I know if it can be smaller than this.
我知道它是否可以比这个更小。
But if you want to be higher than entropy,
但如果你想高于熵，
there are different codes and methods.
有不同的代码和方法。
The half-code is the smallest.
半码是最小的。
It is not necessarily the same as entropy.
它不一定与熵相同。
Sometimes it will be higher than entropy.
有时它会高于熵。
But I read in the CSDN,
但我在CSDN上看到，
it can say that this question is 00 and 10.
可以说这道题是00和10。
But I can say that...
但我可以说...
Because it is different from the latter,
因为它与后者不同，
I can use 0 and 1 to express it.
我可以用0和1来表达。
Because the design of the half-code
因为半码的设计
is not just about the average number of bits,
不仅仅是平均位数，
or symbol.
或符号。
That is not the only thing.
这还不是唯一的事情。
So we can consider uniquely decodable.
所以我们可以考虑唯一可解码。
When you have a bitstream,
当你有比特流时，
it must have no half-code.
它必须没有半码。
It must have only one way to decode it.
它必须只有一种解码方式。
If you do not know the process,
如果您不知道流程，
when you decode it,
当你解码它时，
sometimes it will have a half-code.
有时它会有半码。
You have to cut it into different symbols.
你必须把它切成不同的符号。
It will have a mess.
将会一团糟。
When I press and hold the button,
当我按住按钮时，
it may change.
它可能会改变。
It will not know where to cut.
它不知道该切到哪里。
If you use half-code,
如果您使用半代码，
it has a concept called uniquely decodable.
它有一个称为唯一可解码的概念。
You have to use this method to cut it into symbols.
你必须用这个方法把它切成符号。
So it must be using 00 and 10 to express the difference between 0 and 10.
所以它一定是用00和10来表示0和10之间的差异。
This is the probability.
这就是概率。
If it is not half-code,
如果不是半码，
or if I use other codes to express it,
或者如果我用其他代码来表达它，
it can cut it into shorter symbols.
它可以将其切成更短的符号。
Half-mode pudding can actually be calculated as the shortest.
半模布丁其实可以计算为最短的。
You mean it is the shortest.
你的意思是它是最短的。
It is not shorter than it.
它并不比它短。
I understand. Thank you.
我明白。谢谢。
This is the method.
这就是方法。
OK.
好的。
I want to ask about the official website.
我想问一下官方网站。
I saw that you have a new project.
我看到你有一个新项目。
But a student said that she is not doing it.
但一名学生表示，她并没有这样做。
She wants to change to another project.
她想换一个项目。
So you have one?
那么你有一个吗？
I see that there is a problem with the system.
我发现系统有问题。
There is one now.
现在有一个了。
It is because a student has launched it.
这是因为有一个学生发起了它。
I will show you the link later.
稍后我会向您展示链接。
You can show me.
你可以给我看看。
I have an account.
我有一个帐户。
OK.
好的。
I want to ask about this.
我想问一下这个问题。
It should not be three people to express this.
这不应该是三个人来表达的。
It is two people.
这是两个人。
It means that N is smaller than M.
这意味着N小于M。
But I saw that you wrote N is smaller than 0.33.
但我看到你写的N小于0.33。
It is bigger than 0.
它大于 0。
It should not be smaller than 0.27.
不应小于0.27。
It should be smaller than half of this.
它应该小于这个的一半。
OK.
好的。
Because this A is not the ideal code.
因为这个A并不是理想的代码。
It is designed by someone.
它是由某人设计的。
It is the ideal code.
这是理想的代码。
So this is only for the Pokemon code.
所以这仅适用于 Pokemon 代码。
Only higher code will be smaller.
只有更高的代码才会更小。
Yes.
是的。
The other idea is that the code A is designed by someone.
另一种想法是代码A是由某人设计的。
So it does not follow the code.
所以它不遵循代码。
This is the code that is designed by someone.
这是某人设计的代码。
Thank you.
谢谢。
I want to ask if you can wear a calculator when you take the exam?
我想问一下考试的时候可以带计算器吗？
What calculator?
什么计算器？
When you take the exam.
当你参加考试的时候。
What should I wear?
我应该穿什么？
Calculator.
计算器。
I just draw this when I take the exam.
我考试的时候就画了这个。
Or I have to draw this?
还是我必须画这个？
Generally, it is better to draw all the steps.
一般来说，最好把所有的步骤都画出来。
Because it is like this.
因为事情就是这样的。
Because it is like this when we change.
因为当我们改变的时候就是这样。
We change it like this.
我们这样改。
Because we have to change the words in a short time.
因为我们必须在短时间内改变文字。
So we usually look at the answer.
所以我们通常都会看答案。
If the answer is the same as the words,
如果答案与文字相同，
we will not understand it.
我们不会理解它。
Because it is not possible to say that the process is wrong and the answer is wrong.
因为不可能说过程错了，答案也错了。
So if the answer is wrong, we look at the artist and give the artist a point.
因此，如果答案是错误的，我们会关注艺术家并给艺术家一分。
The problem is that if the answer is wrong,
问题是如果答案错误的话
I will look back when the answer is wrong.
当答案错误时我会回头看。
If I find that there is no step,
如果我发现没有步骤，
you just write this to me.
你就写这个给我吧。
Then I will get a point.
然后我会得到一个点。
Understand?
理解？
Our code is calculated from the smallest probability.
我们的代码是根据最小概率计算的。
I saw that there was a probability on the Internet.
我看到网上有一个概率。
I think it is a big and small number.
我认为这是一个大数字和小数字。
In fact, the code is fixed.
其实代码是固定的。
Some people have different methods.
有些人有不同的方法。
We use different methods.
我们使用不同的方法。
Although I started to talk about how to generate this code.
虽然我开始讲的是如何生成这段代码。
Some people use a slightly different method.
有些人使用稍微不同的方法。
We use a standard method.
我们使用标准方法。
The most common one.
最常见的一种。
Because it is a most common method.
因为这是最常用的方法。
So if you want to simplify it,
所以如果你想简化它，
there are several methods that you can find.
您可以找到多种方法。
Although it may not be the fastest,
虽然它可能不是最快的，
it is the most standard.
这是最标准的。
I think we should follow this method.
我认为我们应该遵循这个方法。
I suggest you use this method.
我建议你使用这个方法。
Because the time difference is not too big.
因为时差不是太大。
So it is 4 plus 4.
所以是4加4。
That is why it is big here.
这就是为什么这里很大。
But most of the questions are given in the following.
但大多数问题都在下面给出。
Therefore, the examples given in the exercises are the more common ones.
因此，练习中给出的例子是比较常见的。
This is just an example.
这只是一个例子。
This example is by occurrence.
这个例子是偶然发生的。
But most of the time it is given in the following.
但大多数情况下是在下面给出的。
Then we will talk about the step.
然后我们再讲一下步骤。
This is the step.
这就是步骤。
If I draw the numbers and know that they are related,
如果我画出数字并知道它们是相关的，
then in this case, I need to consider the size of M0.15.
那么在这种情况下，我需要考虑M0.15的尺寸。
Or this situation will not appear?
或者说这种情况不会出现？
If I understand your question,
如果我理解你的问题
you mean if the
你的意思是如果
If the
如果
The question just now
刚才的问题
is not the one that provides the number 1111.
不是提供号码 1111 的人。
The reason is that
原因是
if I cross a number of steps,
如果我跨过许多台阶，
I will get the number of steps.
我会得到步数。
Do you know that question?
你知道这个问题吗？
Generally speaking,
一般来说，
we can do it in one direction.
我们可以朝一个方向去做。
I know.
我知道。
I don't think it will appear in the question.
我认为它不会出现在问题中。
Generally speaking,
一般来说，
it will not appear.
它不会出现。
I heard that student said
我听那位同学说
that it is reasonable.
这是合理的。
I am sorry.
对不起。
Okay.
好的。
Welcome back.
欢迎回来。
Let's continue on with the
让我们继续
image or video compression basics.
图像或视频压缩基础知识。
Why do we want to perform
我们为什么要表演
image or video compression?
图像或视频压缩？
Earlier on, I already mentioned
前面我已经提到过
for media types such as
对于媒体类型，例如
image and video,
图像和视频，
the data storage requirement is very large.
数据存储需求非常大。
If you do not compress it,
如果不压缩的话
then it is very hard for us
那么我们就很难了
to either store or transmit it.
存储或传输它。
That is the key motivation.
这是关键动机。
Why do we want to do that?
我们为什么要这么做？
That is the key motivation.
这是关键动机。
Why do we want to perform the compression?
为什么我们要进行压缩？
You can see that
你可以看到
image and video compression is necessary
图像和视频压缩是必要的
for two reasons.
有两个原因。
One is to reduce the storage requirement.
一是减少存储需求。
The other is that if you want to
另一个是如果你想
transmit over the network,
通过网络传输，
then you can reduce the bitrate
那么你可以降低比特率
or the bandwidth requirement.
或带宽要求。
The next question is that
下一个问题是
we know that there is a motivation
我们知道有一个动机
why we need to perform the compression.
为什么我们需要执行压缩。
But what is so special
但有什么特别的
about this media type
关于此媒体类型
that allows us to perform the compression?
这允许我们执行压缩？
The next question is
下一个问题是
why is it possible to perform the compression?
为什么可以执行压缩？
The reason why
原因是
for image and video
用于图像和视频
it is possible for us to compress it
我们可以压缩它
is because it contains some redundancy.
是因为它包含一些冗余。
What is the meaning of
是什么意思
this word redundancy?
这个词冗余？
This word redundancy
这个词冗余
means that it is the extra
意味着这是额外的
unnecessary information
不必要的信息
that is captured in the
被捕获在
image and video domain.
图像和视频域。
There are two types of redundancy
冗余有两种类型
in terms of image and video.
在图像和视频方面。
The first one is known as
第一个被称为
the statistical redundancy.
统计冗余。
It is the extra unnecessary
这是多余的不必要的
information from the
信息来自
statistical viewpoint.
统计观点。
The first type is the spatial redundancy.
第一类是空间冗余。
This word spatial,
空间这个词，
what is the word spatial?
空间这个词是什么？
Spatial means it is a space-based redundancy.
空间意味着它是基于空间的冗余。
Space-based redundancy
天基冗余
means that it is a redundancy
意味着这是一个冗余
that exists in an image.
存在于图像中。
Anyway, this slide will just give
无论如何，这张幻灯片只会给出
a quick overview.
快速概述。
Afterwards, for the next few slides, we are going to
之后，在接下来的几张幻灯片中，我们将
explain a little bit more
多解释一下
in detail. Therefore,
详细。所以，
spatial redundancy refers to
空间冗余是指
the redundancy that exists in a
存在的冗余
single image or single
单幅图像或单幅图像
frame.
框架。
The next word is the temporal redundancy.
下一个词是时间冗余。
Temporal come from
时间来自
the base term time.
基本术语时间。
It is a time-based redundancy.
这是基于时间的冗余。
When you think about time-based redundancy,
当您考虑基于时间的冗余时，
what comes to your mind right away are
你立刻想到的是
things like audio or
诸如音频或
video. For video,
视频。对于视频，
it is nothing but a sequence of frames.
它只不过是一系列帧。
Across
穿过
two different frames, usually because
两个不同的框架，通常是因为
for the motion to appear to be
该动议看起来是
smooth, each frame must be
平滑，每一帧都必须
very similar to the next frame.
与下一帧非常相似。
What it means is that the movement
这意味着运动
of, for example, an object in one
例如，一个物体中的一个
frame and the next frame, they are very
帧和下一帧，它们非常
similar. If these two
相似的。如果这两个
frames are very similar, that means there are lots of
框架非常相似，这意味着有很多
extra,
额外的，
they are very similar, that means there are lots of
它们非常相似，这意味着有很多
extra unnecessary information
额外的不必要的信息
that exists across a frame.
跨框架存在的。
And across a frame, because
跨过一个框架，因为
this frame is in the
该帧位于
time axis, so that's why
时间轴，所以这就是为什么
it's also known as a temporal
它也被称为时间
redundancy. So,
冗余。所以，
this is the redundancy that exists in
这就是存在的冗余
the video. Okay, the next
视频。好的，下一个
one is the coding redundancy.
一是编码冗余。
Coding redundancy is the extra
编码冗余是额外的
unnecessary information that exists
存在不必要的信息
in terms of how you
就你如何
represent the information. Like, for
代表信息。喜欢，为了
example, early on we compare
例如，一开始我们比较
uncompressed versus
未压缩与
Huffman coding. So, it's the types of
霍夫曼编码。所以，它的类型是
coding redundancy.
编码冗余。
If you don't perform things like Huffman
如果你不执行像霍夫曼那样的事情
coding. So, the next types
编码。所以，接下来的类型
of redundancy that we have is called
我们拥有的冗余称为
psychovisual redundancy.
心理视觉冗余。
So, psychovisual is how
那么，心理视觉是如何
human visual system perceives
人类视觉系统感知
an object. Okay? So, specifically,
一个物体。好的？所以，具体来说，
there are two types. One is the frequency masking.
有两种类型。一是频率掩蔽。
So, frequency masking
所以，频率掩蔽
actually means that, you know, how our
实际上意味着，你知道，我们如何
eye perceives to different frequency
眼睛感知到不同的频率
components. So, our eyes
成分。那么，我们的眼睛
are more sensitive to
更敏感
any changes or noise
任何变化或噪音
in smooth regions. Okay?
在光滑区域。好的？
And it's, you know, less sensitive
你知道，它不太敏感
to any distortion in the
任何扭曲
texture region. So, one very
纹理区域。所以，一个非常
simple example is, you know,
简单的例子是，你知道，
if you look at, for example, the shirt I'm
例如，如果你看一下我的衬衫
wearing here is quite
穿在这里还蛮
smooth. So, you can see there's this
光滑的。所以，你可以看到有这个
patch here. So, this is
补丁在这里。所以，这是
when, this patch here, that means
当，这个补丁在这里，这意味着
actually it's low frequency region.
实际上是低频区域。
So, if there's particular spots
所以，如果有特别的地方
here, most of you will be able
在这里，你们中的大多数人都能够
to spot it quite readily.
很容易发现它。
So, this is because our eyes are more
所以，这是因为我们的眼睛更多
sensitive to any noise or
对任何噪音或敏感
distortion in low frequency
低频失真
region. Okay? Anyway, later
地区。好的？无论如何，以后
on we'll explain a little bit more.
我们将进一步解释一下。
This color masking is actually
这个颜色掩蔽实际上是
based on what we discussed last time.
基于我们上次讨论的内容。
Our eyes are more sensitive to the
我们的眼睛对光线更加敏感
brightness or the luminance component
亮度或亮度分量
and less sensitive to
并且不太敏感
the color or the
颜色或
chrominance component. So, we can also
色度分量。那么，我们也可以
use that to help us to perform
用它来帮助我们执行
image and video compression.
图像和视频压缩。
So, because there are lots of
所以，因为有很多
redundancy across this
这方面的冗余
statistical and psycho-visual
统计和心理视觉
redundancy, that's why it allows us to
冗余，这就是为什么它允许我们
perform decompression.
执行减压。
Right, okay. So, next
对了，好吧。那么，接下来
we are going to explain a little bit more
我们将进一步解释一下
about each of these
关于其中每一个
redundancy a bit more in detail.
冗余更详细一些。
So, the first one is a spatial redundancy.
所以，第一个是空间冗余。
So, spatial redundancy
所以，空间冗余
refers to the statistical correlation.
指统计相关性。
So, correlation means
所以，相关性意味着
similarity or relatedness
相似性或相关性
between
之间
pixels within an image
图像内的像素
or more specifically, within a small
或者更具体地说，在一个小范围内
image neighborhood
图像邻域
here. So,
这里。所以，
spatial redundancy, pretty much the high-level
空间冗余，几乎是高层的
concept is like this. So, if you
概念是这样的。所以，如果你
look at the image, okay, and specifically
看图片，好吧，具体一点
if you look at a small
如果你看一个小
kind of image
图像的种类
region, the pixel values
区域，像素值
tends to be quite similar
往往非常相似
to each other. For most
彼此。对于大多数人来说
natural image, right, we are
自然形象，对，我们是
talking about most natural image,
谈论最自然的形象，
if you look at a small pixel
如果你看一个小像素
neighborhood or image neighborhood,
邻域或图像邻域，
the pixel values tends to be
像素值往往是
very similar to each other.
彼此非常相似。
So, if the pixel values tends to be
因此，如果像素值趋向于
very similar to each other,
彼此非常相似，
that means there is lots of extra
这意味着还有很多额外的
unnecessary information
不必要的信息
that exists in a small
存在于一个小
image region. Because
图像区域。因为
instead of representing each pixel
而不是代表每个像素
in this small image region,
在这个小图像区域中，
you actually just need
你实际上只需要
to have one single pixel, it can
拥有一个像素，它可以
more or less represent this region already.
或多或少已经代表了这个地区。
So, if
所以，如果
you are using every single pixel
你正在使用每一个像素
to represent this image region,
来表示该图像区域，
that means you exist lots
这意味着你存在很多
of redundant information
冗余信息
already. So, this kind of redundancy
已经。所以，这种冗余
is known as the
被称为
spatial redundancy.
空间冗余。
So, for example, if you
因此，举例来说，如果您
look at this image here, if you
看看这张图片，如果你
look at a small image region, for example
例如，查看一个小图像区域
here, you can see within this small
在这里，你可以看到这个小
image region or patch,
图像区域或补丁，
the pixel values are very similar to
像素值非常相似
each other. So, if the pixel values
彼此。所以，如果像素值
are very similar to each other,
彼此非常相似，
that means there is lots of redundant information
这意味着有很多冗余信息
there. But there is no need actually
那里。但实际上没有必要
for you to represent each
让你代表每一个
pixel.
像素。
So, this type of redundancy
所以，这种类型的冗余
is also known as the intra-frame redundancy.
也称为帧内冗余。
Intra means
内部手段
routine. So, it's the redundancy
常规。所以，这就是冗余
that exists
存在的
within one single frame.
在一帧内。
So, therefore, spatial
因此，空间
redundancy is actually
冗余实际上是
also known as the intra-frame redundancy.
也称为帧内冗余。
Redundancy that exists across
存在冗余
a single image or frame.
单个图像或帧。
So, the
所以，
next one is the temporal redundancy.
下一个是时间冗余。
So, temporal redundancy, as I mentioned,
所以，正如我提到的，时间冗余，
I actually explained to you earlier.
其实我之前就跟你解释过了。
So, let's look at the definition.
那么，让我们看看定义。
So, temporal redundancy refers to the
因此，时间冗余是指
statistical correlation.
统计相关性。
So, this word correlation means
所以，这个词相关性的意思是
similarity or relatedness.
相似性或相关性。
Between pixels from successive
连续像素之间
frames in a video sequence.
视频序列中的帧。
So, if you look at this particular example
所以，如果你看看这个特定的例子
here, this is different frames in
在这里，这是不同的框架
a video, just as we mentioned.
正如我们提到的，视频。
In a video,
在一个视频中，
if you have many different frames, and for
如果你有很多不同的框架，并且对于
this particular video to appear to be
这个特定的视频似乎是
smooth, each of the frames are
流畅，每一帧都是
very similar to each other.
彼此非常相似。
So, if you, for example, look at a small
所以，举例来说，如果你看一个小
image
图像
regions here,
这里的地区，
you can see this current
你可以看到这个电流
frame and the
框架和
next frame, they'll be very similar.
下一帧，它们将非常相似。
So, if these regions are very similar,
所以，如果这些区域非常相似，
that means there are lots of
这意味着有很多
extra unnecessary
额外不必要的
information, or what we call redundancy.
信息，或者我们所说的冗余。
So, this kind of redundancy
所以，这种冗余
exists across
存在于
the frame axis or the time axis.
帧轴或时间轴。
So, that's why it's called
所以，这就是为什么它被称为
temporal redundancy.
时间冗余。
So, temporal redundancy is also
所以，时间冗余也是
known as inter-frame redundancy.
称为帧间冗余。
So, you can guess more or less why that's
所以，你或多或少可以猜到为什么会这样
the case, because it's the redundant
这种情况，因为它是多余的
information that exists across
存在于各处的信息
different frames, specifically
不同的框架，特别是
for video.
对于视频。
Right, so, next one is
对了，那么，下一篇是
the coding redundancy.
编码冗余。
So, coding redundancy actually is
所以，编码冗余实际上是
how you represent the
你如何代表
information, just like in our
信息，就像我们的
previous part when we talked about entropy
上一部分我们讨论熵时
coding. You can already
编码。你已经可以
see just by analyzing
仅通过分析即可看到
the data a little bit more
数据多一点
carefully, and then try to
仔细地，然后尝试
assign shorter
分配较短的
code work to more probable
代码工作更有可能
symbol and longer code work to less
符号和较长的代码可以减少工作量
probable symbol, you can already
可能的符号，你已经可以
reduce the number of bits
减少位数
to represent the symbol. So,
来表示符号。所以，
this is a type of coding
这是一种编码类型
redundancy. So, that means if you don't
冗余。所以，这意味着如果你不这样做
exploit those properties, then there's
利用这些属性，然后就有
lots of redundant information
大量冗余信息
in your, like, fixed length
在你的固定长度中
representation already.
代表已经。
Okay, so coding redundancy
好的，所以编码冗余
focus on representation of the information
注重信息的表达
or the code itself. Right, so
或代码本身。对了，所以
the easiest way to understand this
理解这一点的最简单方法
is through an example.
是通过一个例子。
So, you look at this example here. Suppose we have
所以，你在这里看看这个例子。假设我们有
five symbols, A1 to A5,
五个符号，A1 至 A5，
and this is the probability of occurrence.
这就是发生的概率。
So, now, based on what you
所以，现在，根据你的情况
have studied in the previous part, you can see
上一部分学过，可以看到
there's a few different ways you can represent
有几种不同的方式可以表示
these
这些
symbols using the bit patterns.
使用位模式的符号。
So, one simple way, if you use a very
所以，一个简单的方法，如果你使用一个非常
naive way, which is
天真的方式，即
uniform length coding
统一长度编码
or fixed length coding,
或固定长度编码，
because you have five symbols,
因为你有五个符号，
so you can actually use three bits
所以你实际上可以使用三位
to represent. So, if you decided
代表。所以，如果你决定
to use three bits to represent each
使用三位来表示每个
symbol, okay, for example, you use
符号，好的，例如，你使用
this bit pattern
这个位模式
to represent this symbol. So, you can see
来表示这个符号。所以，你可以看到
in this case, the average
在这种情况下，平均
number of bits that's required to represent
需要表示的位数
a symbol is actually three bits.
一个符号实际上是三位。
But, on the other hand, if
但是，另一方面，如果
you're a little bit more clever, especially after
你聪明了一点，尤其是在
you have studied the
你已经研究过
first part of the lecture, you know that
讲座的第一部分，你知道
for those
对于那些
symbols that has a higher probability,
概率较高的符号，
we should assign a shorter
我们应该分配一个更短的
code. Those with a lower probability,
代码。那些概率较低的人，
we should assign a longer
我们应该分配一个更长的
code. Just by being a little bit more
代码。只要多一点点
clever about it, using
巧妙地利用它
this variable length coding,
这种可变长度编码，
if you try to calculate
如果你尝试计算
the average number of bits per
每的平均位数
symbol, so like what
符号，就像什么
we mentioned just now, probability multiplied
刚才我们提到，概率成倍增加
with the number of bits, in this case it's four
与位数，在本例中为四
bits,
位，
probability of 0.2 multiplied with
0.2 的概率乘以
two bits, by repeating the process
两位，通过重复该过程
that we have explained earlier,
我们之前已经解释过，
we can see we can obtain 1.95.
我们可以看到我们可以得到1.95。
So, in other words, what it means
所以，换句话说，这意味着什么
is that just if you are a bit more
就是只要你多一点
clever, if you can come up with some
聪明，如果你能想出一些
more intelligent
更聪明
way of designing your code,
设计代码的方式，
actually you can
实际上你可以
achieve better
取得更好的成绩
efficiency or representation.
效率或代表性。
So, that means in terms of code itself,
所以，这意味着就代码本身而言，
there's some kind of redundancy.
存在某种冗余。
If you don't do anything, there's some redundancy
如果你什么都不做，就会有一些冗余
inside that you can exploit
里面你可以利用
to remove it.
将其删除。
So, the next one that
那么，下一篇
we mentioned is a psychovisual redundancy.
我们提到的是心理视觉冗余。
So, the first one is
所以，第一个是
frequency masking. So, earlier on,
频率掩蔽。所以，早些时候，
I mentioned that human
我提到过人类
is less sensitive to noise or distortion
对噪声或失真不太敏感
in the high frequency component.
在高频成分中。
So, this frequency masking
所以，这个频率掩蔽
is like this.
是这样的。
So, I believe most of you have
所以，我相信你们大多数人都有
studied time-based signals.
研究基于时间的信号。
So, for time-based signals,
因此，对于基于时间的信号，
for example, if you are measuring the
例如，如果您正在测量
temperature in this room, the
这个房间的温度，
horizontal axis is the time,
横轴是时间，
vertical axis is the temperature.
纵轴是温度。
So, then you have the signal,
那么，你就有信号了，
time-based signal, which looks like that.
基于时间的信号，看起来像那样。
So, we know that for time-based
所以，我们知道对于基于时间的
signal, when you say
信号，当你说
for a time-based signal, it has high
对于基于时间的信号，它具有高
frequency component.
频率分量。
What does that mean? If you have
这意味着什么？如果你有
a time-based signal, for example,
基于时间的信号，例如
temperature in this room,
这个房间的温度，
and you say that
你这么说
this time-based signal or temperature
这个基于时间的信号或温度
in this room has high frequency
在这个房间里出现的频率很高
component, what does that mean?
组件，什么意思？
It means that your signal is
这意味着你的信号是
fluctuating very quickly.
波动非常快。
High frequency means that it's changing
高频意味着它在变化
very quickly. So, that's the interpretation
非常快。那么，这就是解释
in the time domain,
在时域中，
which is a 1D signal.
这是一个一维信号。
But, if you are talking about image domain,
但是，如果你谈论的是图像域，
so for image domain, what we
所以对于图像域，我们
have is that, for example,
有的是，例如，
this image here,
这张图片在这里，
we have the x-y coordinate
我们有 x-y 坐标
system,
系统，
x and y coordinate system.
x 和 y 坐标系。
And then afterwards, from last lecture,
然后，从上次讲座开始，
we know we have different pixels.
我们知道我们有不同的像素。
If you look at each of the RGB
如果你看一下每个 RGB
channel value,
通道值，
it can be interpreted as a
它可以被解释为
z-value, the
z 值，
z-axis value. So, therefore,
z 轴值。所以，因此，
for an image like this,
对于这样的图像，
this is the x and y
这是 x 和 y
coordinate system, and each
坐标系，并且每个
of the RGB channel can be
RGB 通道的值可以是
interpreted as the z-value,
解释为 z 值，
or like the mountain and valley,
或者像高山和山谷，
the landscape. So, therefore,
风景。所以，因此，
for an image like this,
对于这样的图像，
you can interpret it like,
你可以把它解释为
you have a landscape,
你有一片风景，
you have mountains and valleys.
你有山脉和山谷。
So, if these particular mountains
所以，如果这些特定的山脉
and valleys change very quickly,
山谷变化得很快，
then we say that this image
然后我们说这个图像
has high frequency component.
具有高频成分。
And if,
如果，
for example, in this particular image,
例如，在这张特定的图像中，
these regions here,
这里的这些地区，
you can see the pixel value change
可以看到像素值的变化
very slowly. So, this is the
非常慢。所以，这就是
x and y coordinate. If the
x 和 y 坐标。如果
pixel value change very slowly,
像素值变化非常缓慢，
then we say it has low frequency component.
那么我们就说它有低频成分。
But if the pixel value
但如果像素值
change very quickly, we can say
变化非常快，我们可以说
that it has high frequency component.
它具有高频成分。
So, this is the interpretation for
所以，这就是对
image and video, when we are
图像和视频，当我们
talking about a high or
谈论高或
low frequency content. So,
低频内容。所以，
therefore, if we take this particular
因此，如果我们采取这个特殊的
image here, you can see that this image mainly
图片在这里，你可以看到这张图片主要是
has low frequency content,
具有低频内容，
because the pixel values change very
因为像素值变化很大
slowly. Okay? In a small region,
慢慢地。好的？在一个小区域内，
the pixel value changes slowly.
像素值变化缓慢。
But this particular image, we
但是这个特殊的图像，我们
can say that it has high frequency component,
可以说它具有高频成分，
because in a lot of these
因为在很多这些
small regions, the pixel value
小区域，像素值
change very quickly. So, this is
变化很快。所以，这是
the high-frequency- this image has lots of
高频 - 该图像有很多
high frequency component. This
高频成分。这
image has lots of low-frequency
图像有很多低频
component. Okay?
成分。好的？
So, now we know how to interpret
所以，现在我们知道如何解释
the meaning of low frequency
低频的含义
and high frequency component. Next,
和高频成分。下一个，
we look at just now the example
我们看一下刚才的例子
that we mentioned. Right, okay.
我们提到过。对了，好吧。
So, again, we take the example of
所以，我们再次举个例子
the clothes I'm wearing today. Right?
我今天穿的衣服。正确的？
So, this particular- the clothes
所以，这个特别的——衣服
I'm wearing today mainly has
我今天穿的主要有
lots of low-frequency component,
大量的低频成分，
because you can see lots of regions
因为你可以看到很多地区
changing very slowly. So,
变化非常缓慢。所以，
our eyes are very sensitive to any
我们的眼睛对任何事物都非常敏感
noise or distortion,
噪声或失真，
or changes in low-frequency region.
或低频区域的变化。
So, what I'm trying to say is, imagine
所以，我想说的是，想象一下
if just now dinner time, I eat some
如果现在是晚餐时间，我吃一些
noodle, and then there's a spot here,
面条，然后这里有一个地方，
right, most of you will be able to
是的，你们中的大多数人都能够
identify quite quickly. Right? Because
识别得相当快。正确的？因为
if this is a low-frequency region,
如果这是一个低频区域，
if there's any noise or distortion
是否有任何噪音或失真
in low-frequency region, our eyes
在低频区域，我们的眼睛
can notice it very quickly.
可以很快注意到它。
Yeah. So, as opposed to that,
是的。所以，与此相反，
right, for example, if I'm wearing
是的，例如，如果我穿着
a shirt, which has
一件衬衫，上面有
lots of vertical stripe, you know,
很多垂直条纹，你知道，
if there's a shirt with lots of- or
如果有一件衬衫有很多-或
checkered shirt, you know, checkered shirt,
格子衬衫，你知道，格子衬衫，
yeah, and if I have the same spots,
是的，如果我也有同样的地方，
most of you will not be able to notice it,
大多数人都无法注意到它，
because our eyes are not so sensitive
因为我们的眼睛没那么敏感
to any changes in high-
对高的任何变化
frequency component. So, that's one example.
频率分量。这就是一个例子。
So, if you take this example,
所以，如果你拿这个例子来说，
we can see this image has
我们可以看到这张图片有
low-frequency component,
低频分量，
so if there's any distortion,
所以如果有任何扭曲
for example, if there's a small bird here,
举例来说，如果这里有一只小鸟，
most of you will be able to spot
你们中的大多数人都能发现
it very quickly. As opposed to
很快。相对于
this, suppose this is an image
这个，假设这是一个图像
with high-frequency component,
具有高频成分，
if there's a small bird here, most of you
如果这里有一只小鸟，你们大多数人
cannot see it so quickly.
不能这么快看到它。
So, this particular thing is known as
所以，这个特殊的东西被称为
the frequency masking. A human
频率掩蔽。一个人
is more sensitive to noise or distortion
对噪声或失真更敏感
in- is less sensitive,
in- 不太敏感，
less sensitive to noise and distortion
对噪声和失真不太敏感
in high-frequency
在高频
component. So, the reverse
成分。那么，反过来
means that it's more sensitive
意味着它更敏感
to noise and distortion in low-frequency
低频噪声和失真
component. So, this
成分。所以，这个
property will be exploited
财产将被剥削
later on when we study about
稍后当我们学习时
image and video compression.
图像和视频压缩。
So, later on, we'll- when we come to
所以，稍后，当我们来到
the necessary place, I'll explain
必要的地方我会解释一下
a little bit more. So, the next
再多一点。那么，接下来
one is that colour masking.
一是颜色掩蔽。
So, human is more sensitive to the
所以，人类对
luminance or the brightness
亮度或亮度
component. Sometimes we also call
成分。有时我们也打电话
it the luma, okay?
它是亮度，好吗？
Then, the colour or the
然后，颜色或
chrominance or the chroma component.
色度或色度分量。
So, this point we have actually explained
所以，这一点我们实际上已经解释过了
in last lecture
在上一讲中
as well. So, this is also
以及。所以，这也是
another property that
另一个属性
we exploit to
我们利用
perform image and video
执行图像和视频
compression. So, how do we do that?
压缩。那么，我们该怎么做呢？
So, the first thing is that
所以，第一件事是
for those colour channel,
对于那些颜色通道，
so if you remember
所以如果你还记得
in previous lecture, we say that
在上一讲中，我们说
in image and video compression,
在图像和视频压缩方面，
very often we represent the image in
很多时候我们将图像表示为
Y, C, B, C, R kind of colour model.
Y、C、B、C、R 种颜色模型。
And Y is the component,
Y 是分量，
C, B and C, R is the colour
C、B和C、R是颜色
component. So, because our eyes are
成分。所以，因为我们的眼睛
not so sensitive to the C, B and C,
对C、B和C不太敏感，
R, the colour component,
R，颜色分量，
we can afford to drop some of the
我们有能力放弃一些
sample. So, that is the
样本。所以，这就是
idea that will be used later on,
稍后将使用的想法，
as we will see later,
我们稍后会看到，
to perform image and video
执行图像和视频
compression.
压缩。
Right, okay, so,
对啊，好吧，所以，
I think about
我想
10 years ago, around 10 years
10年前，大约10年
ago, this is a very famous kind of
以前，这是一种非常著名的
image.
图像。
I'm just wondering whether
我只是想知道是否
any one of you has seen this image before?
你们中有人以前见过这张图片吗？
Any one of you
你们中的任何一个人
has seen this image? That means you are
看过这个图片吗？这意味着你是
all very young.
都非常年轻。
I think it's more than 10
我认为超过10个
or 15 years ago already.
或者已经是15年前了。
Right, okay, so this particular
好的，好的，所以这个特别
image, what is so interesting about this image
图片，这张图片有什么有趣的地方
is that different person
是不同的人吗
will perceive this
会察觉到这一点
image differently. Okay,
图像不同。好的，
so, I just want to
所以，我只想
check, okay, how many
检查一下，好的，有多少
of you can see this particular image
你可以看到这个特定的图像
as a gold and white
作为金色和白色
colour? Gold and white.
颜色？金色和白色。
Can you just raise your hand?
你能举手吗？
If you see this particular
如果你看到这个特别的
dress, the colour is
衣服，颜色是
white and gold. Please raise your hand.
白色和金色。请举手。
Wow, okay, your class, not so many, but
哇，好吧，你们的班级，没有那么多，但是
some to see it. Okay,
有些人会看到它。好的，
so, some other people, what
那么，其他一些人，什么
other colour do you see?
你看到其他颜色了吗？
Black and?
黑和？
Black and blue, right? So some of you see
黑色和蓝色，对吗？所以你们有些人看到
as black and blue.
如黑色和蓝色。
Can I just have a show of hands?
我可以举手吗？
I just want to see the
我只想看看
statistics roughly. Black,
粗略统计一下。黑色的，
who of you see black
你们谁看到黑色
and blue?
和蓝色？
Okay, I think more
好吧，我想多了
than just now the gold and
比刚才的黄金和
white. Actually,
白色的。实际上，
for myself, I see it as white
对于我自己来说，我认为它是白色的
and gold colour. This is gold colour
和金色。这是金色的颜色
and this is white colour.
这是白色的。
So, okay, so actually this is one of the
所以，好吧，实际上这是其中之一
images that account
说明的图像
it depends on
这取决于
human vision system. Therefore, human vision system
人类视觉系统。因此，人类视觉系统
is very imprecise. Different people
是非常不精确的。不同的人
would perceive it differently.
会有不同的看法。
So, according to some studies,
所以，根据一些研究，
they say that it depends on
他们说这取决于
each individual's
每个人的
types of, you know, how many
类型，你知道，有多少
rod and cone
杆和锥
perceive different colour.
感知不同的颜色。
So, that's why some of you will see
所以，这就是为什么你们中的一些人会看到
the colour slightly differently.
颜色略有不同。
So, there's no right and wrong, it's just
所以，没有什么对错之分，只是
how human vision system
人类视觉系统如何
perceives it.
感知到它。
And then later on, there was someone who actually
然后后来真的有人
take an image. So, because
拍摄一张照片。所以，因为
what happened is that, you know, person who
发生的事情是，你知道，那个人
see as white and yellow,
看到白色和黄色，
they do not know what other people are
他们不知道其他人是什么
seeing. And other people see
看到。而其他人看到的
black and blue,
黑色和蓝色，
they also do not know what other people are
他们也不知道其他人是什么
seeing. So, this is one image
看到。所以，这是一张图片
that try to show
试图展示
what the other party
对方什么
see. So, according to what they say,
看。所以，按照他们的说法，
some people see this colour
有些人看到这个颜色
white and gold, some people
白色和金色，有些人
see this colour more like closer
更接近地看到这种颜色
to blue and
到蓝色和
black, but actually I still see
黑色，但实际上我还是看到了
gold and white, but
金色和白色，但是
okay, can some of you who
好的，你们中的一些人可以吗
see
看
black and blue see this gold and
黑色和蓝色看到这个金色和
white here?
这里是白色的吗？
Can some of you see?
你们中的一些人能看到吗？
Okay, or do you see two different
好吧，或者你看到两个不同的
set of colour?
颜色组？
Okay,
好的，
so anyway, this is
所以无论如何，这是
a very interesting thing. Last year
一件非常有趣的事情。去年
actually, I asked a student as well,
其实我也问过一个学生，
it turned out that about two-third of them
事实证明，其中大约三分之二
see them as black and blue,
将它们视为黑色和蓝色，
about one-third see
大约三分之一看到
as yellow and white.
如黄色和白色。
So, obviously I'm the minority
所以，显然我是少数
here as well.
这里也一样。
Right, okay, so
对啊，好吧，所以
let's continue.
让我们继续吧。
Right, okay, so the next
好吧，那么接下来
things we want to explain is this concept
我们要解释的就是这个概念
about lossy and lossless compression.
关于有损和无损压缩。
So, what is the lossy and lossless compression?
那么，什么是有损压缩和无损压缩呢？
So, lossless
所以，无损
compression is like this. So, initially
压缩是这样的。所以，最初
you have the media, right?
你有媒体，对吗？
You perform the compression to make it into
您执行压缩以使其成为
a smaller file size, and afterwards
较小的文件大小，然后
you decompress it
你解压它
to make it into a bigger file size,
使其成为更大的文件大小，
to reconstruct the media.
重建媒体。
So, if you're reconstructed,
所以，如果你重建了，
for example, image, you're
例如，图像，你是
reconstructed data, and your
重建的数据，以及你的
original data are exactly the
原始数据正是
same, then we call it lossless
一样，那么我们称之为无损
compression, because no
压缩，因为没有
information has been lost. Okay?
信息已丢失。好的？
So, therefore that's quite clear. So, that's
所以，这很清楚。那么，那就是
lossless compression. So, as opposed to
无损压缩。所以，相对于
that, lossy compression means that
有损压缩意味着
you have the media, right, or data,
你有媒体、权利或数据，
you compress it to become smaller
你压缩它变得更小
file size, afterwards you
文件大小，之后你
try to decompress it to
尝试将其解压到
reconstruct your data. If your
重建您的数据。如果你的
reconstructed data is different
重建的数据不同
from your original data, then
从你的原始数据，然后
this is known as a lossy compression,
这称为有损压缩，
because some
因为一些
information has been lost already.
信息已经丢失。
Okay? So, therefore the definition
好的？因此，定义
between lossless and lossy compression
无损压缩和有损压缩之间
is quite clear. So, in
是很清楚的。所以，在
most of the typical
大多数典型的
image and video compression,
图像和视频压缩，
do you think most of them
你认为他们中的大多数人
fall under lossy
有损
or lossless compression?
还是无损压缩？
So, now that we understand
所以，现在我们明白了
what's lossy compression and what's
什么是有损压缩以及什么是
lossless compression, in most
无损压缩，在大多数情况下
kind of typical
有点典型
application, right, do you
申请，对吧，你呢
think we use lossless compression
认为我们使用无损压缩
more or lossy compression more?
更多还是有损压缩更多？
Lot?
很多？
Actually, I can't hear
其实我听不到
so clearly. It seems that there are
这么清楚。好像有
a mix of, some
一些的混合
people say it's lossy, some people say
有人说有损，有人说
it's lossless. Right, okay.
它是无损的。对了，好吧。
So, if
所以，如果
you are a beginner, if you have not studied this
如果你还没有学过这个，你是一个初学者
topic before, you will tend to think it's
之前的话题，你会倾向于认为它是
lossless, right, because lossless is good, no information
无损，对吧，因为无损就好，没有信息
is lost. But it turned out that
丢失了。但事实证明
actually we use lossy
实际上我们使用有损
compression more.
压缩更多。
So, what's the reason actually we use lossy
那么，我们实际上使用有损的原因是什么
compression more?
压缩更多？
So, anyone?
那么，有人吗？
What's the reason actually we use a lossy
实际上我们使用有损的原因是什么
compression more, in
压缩更多，在
real life?
现实生活？
So, what's the objective of performing
那么，表演的目的是什么
compression?
压缩？
What's the objective of performing compression?
执行压缩的目的是什么？
You want to
你想要
reduce the number of
减少数量
bits or file size, right?
位或文件大小，对吗？
So, it turned out that lossy compression
所以，事实证明有损压缩
is more effective in compressing
压缩效果更佳
the file into a smaller
将文件压缩成更小的文件
file size as compared to
文件大小相比
lossless compression.
无损压缩。
So, the reason why we use lossy compression
所以，我们使用有损压缩的原因
more is because, right, your
更多的是因为，对吧，你的
compressed file size is actually much
压缩后的文件大小其实很大
smaller as compared to lossless
与无损相比更小
compression. Even though you
压缩。即使你
may have a little bit of distortion,
可能有一点点失真，
but lots of these changes of distortion
但很多失真的变化
is not so perceptible
不太明显
by human. That means when human, you
由人类。这意味着当你是人类时，你
see it, you hardly tell there's
看到它，你很难说有
any difference in it.
任何差异。
So, therefore, that's why lossy compression
因此，这就是有损压缩的原因
is actually more commonly used.
其实更常用。
So, now let's look at this
那么，现在让我们看看这个
lossless compression. So, lossless compression,
无损压缩。所以，无损压缩，
as we have already explained,
正如我们已经解释过的，
your reconstructed image
你的重建图像
is the same as
是一样的
your original image after reconstruction
重建后的原始图像
or decompression. So,
或减压。所以，
we use lossless compression in important
我们在重要的地方使用无损压缩
media such as medical images.
医学图像等媒体。
Because for
因为对于
medical images,
医学图像，
sometimes you don't want to
有时你不想
have any changes. Because any
有任何改变。因为任何
artifacts or any changes,
工件或任何更改，
sometimes the doctor may interpret
有时医生可能会解释
it's actually a cancer. So, therefore,
它实际上是一种癌症。所以，因此，
for those cases, your
对于这些情况，您的
reconstructed data
重建数据
and your original data must be
并且您的原始数据必须是
the same. So, that's
相同。那么，那就是
for lossless compression.
用于无损压缩。
For lossless compression,
对于无损压缩，
we typically use it in media such as
我们通常在媒体中使用它，例如
image and video.
图像和视频。
So, the reason why we use it
所以，我们使用它的原因
in image and video is because if you have image and video,
在图像和视频中是因为如果你有图像和视频，
you compress it and afterwards
你压缩它然后
you reconstruct.
你重建。
You have this reconstructed or
你有这个重建或
decompressed media. Even though
解压缩的媒体。虽然
your original data
你的原始数据
and your reconstructed data are a little
你重建的数据有点
bit different, but from the human
有点不同，但与人类不同
perception,
洞察力，
from the human perception perspective, you can hardly
从人类的感知角度来看，你很难
tell the difference. Just now,
说出区别。现在，
for example, the image that we show,
例如，我们展示的图像，
even the image, different person
即使是图像，不同的人
will perceive it a little bit differently
会有一点不同的看法
already. So, therefore,
已经。所以，因此，
for these types of approach,
对于这些类型的方法，
lossy compression,
有损压缩，
even though your reconstructed data
即使你重建的数据
is different from the original data,
与原始数据不同，
but these two data, actually, there are
但这两个数据，其实是有
so little difference that human
人类的差异如此之小
cannot tell the difference. So, therefore, it's
无法区分。所以，因此，这是
okay, even though they are not exactly the
好吧，尽管它们并不完全是
same, but it's okay because we can hardly
一样，但是没关系，因为我们几乎不能
tell much difference in it.
告诉我们其中有很大的不同。
But the advantage of this now
但现在这样做的好处
is that we can deploy
我们可以部署
method to compress it much better
更好地压缩它的方法
into a smaller file size.
成较小的文件大小。
So, for media like image and video,
因此，对于图像和视频等媒体，
it's not necessary to display
没有必要显示
more information
更多信息
than what human can see or hear.
比人类能看到或听到的。
So, in these types of cases, actually,
所以，在这些类型的情况下，实际上，
the compression technique will
压缩技术将
may discard data
可能会丢弃数据
with little perceived difference by human.
人类几乎察觉不到差异。
That means it will throw away those
这意味着它将扔掉那些
information that human can actually
人类实际上可以得到的信息
not tell much
不多说
difference as compared to the original data.
与原始数据相比的差异。
So, your reconstructed data
所以，你重建的数据
is different, not
是不同的，不是
identical or different from the original
与原件相同或不同
data after decompression.
解压后的数据。
So, that's the basic idea of lossy compression.
这就是有损压缩的基本思想。
So, there's a few different common
所以，有一些不同的共同点
matrix to measure
测量矩阵
for this lossy
对于这个有损
decompression.
减压。
So, first, you have this
所以，首先，你有这个
X, we call it the original data.
X，我们称之为原始数据。
Suppose the original data we call
假设我们调用的原始数据
X, the reconstructed or
X，重建或
decompressed data we call
我们称之为解压缩数据
Y. So, therefore, there's a few
Y. 因此，有一些
different ways we can measure the
我们可以通过不同的方式来衡量
difference between them for lossy
它们之间的有损差异
compression. So, the first one is
压缩。所以，第一个是
known as a mean square error.
称为均方误差。
So, for the mean square error, if you look at the
因此，对于均方误差，如果您查看
equation, you try to take the
等式，你尝试取
difference between your original pixel
与原始像素之间的差异
and
和
the reconstructed pixel.
重建的像素。
And then you square, you sum up over
然后你平方，你总结
all the pixel, for example, in an image.
例如，图像中的所有像素。
And then you divide by
然后你除以
the total number of pixel in the image.
图像中的像素总数。
This is known as a mean square error.
这称为均方误差。
So, obviously,
所以，显然，
the smaller this value is,
这个值越小，
that means the better your reconstructed
这意味着你重建得越好
image is.
图像是。
So, that's the definition of the mean square error.
这就是均方误差的定义。
So, the next one is the signal to
所以，下一个是信号
noise ratio. So, the signal
噪声比。所以，信号
to noise ratio is defined by this equation.
噪声比由该方程定义。
So, this is a signal power.
所以，这是信号功率。
This is the noise power here.
这是这里的噪声功率。
So, the signal power is defined
因此，信号功率定义为
by, right, so the
由，对，所以
this particular symbol here,
这里的这个特殊符号，
the average square value of your
你的平均平方值
original data.
原始数据。
So, each of the pixel value,
所以，每个像素值，
right, you square and then
对了，你平方然后
you take its average, right, so therefore
你取平均值，对吧，所以因此
it's a signal power.
这是信号功率。
And then this noise power,
然后这个噪声功率，
noise power here is actually just now
这里的噪音功率实际上只是现在
the error that we have found
我们发现的错误
earlier on. So, if you take the signal
早些时候。所以，如果你接收到信号
power, the average
功率，平均
signal power divided by the noise
信号功率除以噪声
that we have computed earlier,
我们之前已经计算过，
then this is actually known as a
那么这实际上被称为
signal to noise ratio, or S and R.
信噪比，或 S 和 R。
So, for a good
所以，为了一个好的
reconstructed
重建的
compression method,
压缩方法，
you want your S and R to be as high
你希望你的 S 和 R 一样高
as possible, because you want
尽可能，因为你想要
your noise to be as small as possible.
你的噪音尽可能小。
If your noise is small, that means
如果你的噪音很小，那就意味着
this value will be large.
这个值会很大。
Right, okay, so the third commonly
好的，好的，所以通常是第三个
used matrix is known as peak signal
使用的矩阵称为峰值信号
to noise ratio. So, the peak signal
与噪声之比。所以，峰值信号
to noise ratio, if you look at this
噪声比，如果你看看这个
equation and this equation, they are very similar.
方程和这个方程，它们非常相似。
The only difference now is that
现在唯一的区别是
here, in this signal to noise
在这里，在这个信噪比中
ratio, this is the average signal
比率，这是平均信号
power. But, for this
力量。但是，对于这个
peak signal to noise ratio,
峰值信噪比，
this one here, we just take the maximum
这里，我们只取最大值
value. For example, if you use
价值。例如，如果您使用
8 bits to represent it, then
8位来表示，那么
this value will be 255.
该值将为 255。
Okay, this X peak here
好的，这个 X 峰在这里
will be 255, 255 square.
将是 255, 255 平方。
Okay, so, therefore
好吧，所以，所以
this particular matrix
这个特定的矩阵
is known as peak signal,
称为峰值信号，
the largest value.
最大的值。
Peak signal to noise, noise
峰值信噪比、噪声
is the error. So, peak signal to
是错误。因此，峰值信号
noise ratio. So, this is another
噪声比。所以，这是另一个
common matrix to measure the
通用矩阵来衡量
distortion between your original
与原始内容之间的失真
data and your reconstructed
数据和你重建的
data.
数据。
Right, okay, so the next
好吧，那么接下来
topic we are going to look at now is a
我们现在要讨论的主题是
transform-based coding and compression.
基于变换的编码和压缩。
So, transform coding.
因此，变换编码。
So, why do we want to do transform coding?
那么，我们为什么要进行变换编码呢？
So, what is this idea of transform
那么，这个变换的想法是什么呢？
coding? So, the idea of transform
编码？于是就有了改造的想法
coding is that, right, so you have
编码就是这样，对，所以你有
for example, original
例如，原始的
data, right, so
数据，对，所以
for example, let's start with the image.
例如，让我们从图像开始。
You have some images, right,
你有一些图像，对吧，
you may want to do some transformation
你可能想做一些转变
into a
变成一个
transform domain. So, the
变换域。所以，
image in its original
原始图像
form is called in the pixel domain.
形式在像素域中被称为。
Right, so after you
对了，所以在你之后
have performed some transform, so
已经执行了一些变换，所以
some transform is a mathematical
某些变换是数学上的
operation, right, so you have the
操作，对，所以你有
image in the pixel domain,
像素域中的图像，
you let it go through some transform
你让它经历一些转变
which is a mathematical operation
这是一个数学运算
to get your transform domain
得到你的变换域
or transform kvc.
或改造kvc。
And then afterwards you try to perform compression
然后你尝试执行压缩
in this transform domain
在这个变换域中
using the transform kvc.
使用变换 kvc。
So, at high level,
所以，在高水平上，
why do you want to do that?
你为什么要这么做？
Why do you want to take the data
为什么要拿数据
from the original pixel, right,
从原始像素开始，右，
domain, or the individual pixel
域，或单个像素
to transform it into
将其转变为
some transform domain and
一些变换域和
then perform compression on this transform
然后对此变换执行压缩
domain? Why do we want to do that?
领域？我们为什么要这么做？
So, the reason why
那么，究其原因，
we want to do this mathematical
我们想做这个数学运算
mapping or transformation is
映射或变换是
because, right, the data once
因为，对，数据一次
is transformed into the transform
被转化为变换
domain, it has some good properties
域，它有一些好的属性
that we can exploit
我们可以利用
to perform the compression. At high
来执行压缩。高时
level, this is what it is. It has some
水平，就是这样。它有一些
good property in the transform domain
变换域中良好的特性
that we can use to
我们可以用它来
perform the compression. So, this is a
执行压缩。所以，这是一个
high level idea, and later
高层次的想法，以及后来的
on we are going to take some example and
我们将举一些例子
see this point a lot
经常看到这一点
more clearer.
更清晰。
So, therefore, why do you want to do this
因此，你为什么要这样做
transform? The
转换？这
idea is we want to convert the data
想法是我们要转换数据
into a form, right, which
变成一种形式，对吧，
is more suitable for compression, that means
更适合压缩，这意味着
into the transform domain.
进入变换域。
So, the transformation
所以，转型
may have some good properties. So,
可能有一些好的特性。所以，
one is called energy compaction,
一种称为能量压缩，
the other is to offer
另一个是提供
redundancy reduction.
减少冗余。
So, this energy compaction
所以，这种能量压缩
at high level, what it means is that
在高层次上，这意味着
initially you have this particular
最初你有这个特殊的
image, which is in the pixel domain
图像，位于像素域
or image domain. After
或图像域。后
you have done the transformation, you have
你已经完成了转变，你已经
it in the transform domain. So, this
它在变换域中。所以，这个
energy, right, okay,
能量，对吧，好吧，
the energy will be packed into a small
能量将被打包成一个小
number of kvc. Right, so, in
kvc 数量。对了，所以，在
your original image or pixel domain,
您的原始图像或像素域，
right, okay, how do we measure
好的，好的，我们如何衡量
the energy in the
中的能量
image is that we take
图像是我们采取的
each of the pixel value and we
每个像素值和我们
square. So, each of the
正方形。所以，每个
pixel value, if we square,
像素值，如果我们平方，
that will reflect the energy.
这将反映能量。
So, in the original pixel
所以，在原始像素中
domain, okay, right,
域，好吧，对，
because we do not know
因为我们不知道
each pixel, whether the value
每个像素，是否有值
is large or not. So, therefore, in the
大与否。所以，因此，在
original image or pixel domain,
原始图像或像素域，
we do not know where the energy
我们不知道能量在哪里
is concentrating.
正在集中注意力。
Because if you think about even a
因为如果你想一想
particular image, for
特定图像，对于
each of the pixel value, do you know
每个像素值你知道吗
which pixel value is large
哪个像素值大
or small in advance? You
还是提前小？你
do not know, right. So, therefore,
不知道，对吧。所以，因此，
you do not have a good way to know where
你没有一个好的方法来知道在哪里
the energy is located. But,
能量位于。但，
if you apply the transform,
如果应用变换，
once you have the data in the transform
一旦你有了转换中的数据
domain, you can see most of the energy
域，你可以看到大部分能量
will be concentrated to a small
将集中到一个小
number of kVc.
kVc 数。
So, this is the high level
所以，这就是高水平
kind of explanation.
一种解释。
Later on, when we study about DCT,
后来我们学习DCT的时候，
a lot of this concept will
很多这个概念都会
become a lot more concrete and clear.
变得更加具体和清晰。
So, anyway,
所以，无论如何，
this is the point I was trying to say.
这就是我想说的重点。
But after the transform, the energy
但转化后的能量
will be focusing to
将重点关注
a small number of kVc.
少量kVc。
So, the second
所以，第二个
is that it offers a redundancy
是它提供了冗余
reduction, so which means that
减少，所以这意味着
you reduce the correlation between
你减少了之间的相关性
the transform kVc. So, what it means
变换kVc。那么，这意味着什么
at this point is that if you look at the
此时如果你看一下
original image
原始图像
domain or pixel domain,
域或像素域，
if you know this current pixel,
如果你知道当前像素，
do you think you more or less
你认为你或多或少
know what is the pixel value next to it?
知道它旁边的像素值是多少吗？
In the original
在原作中
image domain,
图像域，
if you know this pixel value,
如果你知道这个像素值，
do you think you more or less know
你认为你或多或少知道
what is the pixel value next to it?
它旁边的像素值是多少？
Yes or no?
是还是不是？
In the
在
image domain, if you know this current
图像域，如果你知道当前的
pixel value, do you think more or less
像素值，你觉得多还是少
you know the pixel value surrounding it?
你知道它周围的像素值吗？
Yes or no?
是还是不是？
In order to answer this question,
为了回答这个问题，
kind of go back to just
有点回到过去
a few slides ago, one of
几张幻灯片前，其中一张
the redundancies that I mentioned to you,
我向你提到的裁员，
which is specifically spatial redundancy.
这具体是空间冗余。
What does spatial
空间有什么作用
redundancy tell you?
冗余告诉你？
If you look at a small
如果你看一个小
pixel neighbourhood,
像素邻域，
the pixel value tends to
像素值趋于
be very
非常
similar to each other. For most natural
彼此相似。对于最自然的
images, that is the case.
图片，就是这样。
If you look at a very small
如果你看一个非常小的
pixel neighbourhood, like for example,
像素邻域，例如，
4x4 or 8x8, the pixel
4x4 或 8x8，像素
values tends to be very similar
价值观往往非常相似
to each other most of the time.
大部分时间都是为了彼此。
So, if the pixel value
所以，如果像素值
tends to be very similar to each other, that means
往往彼此非常相似，这意味着
if you know this current pixel value,
如果你知道当前像素值，
do you think you more or less
你认为你或多或少
can tell what is the pixel value close
可以知道接近的像素值是多少
to it? Yes, right?
到它？是的，对吗？
That's what I've been telling you,
这就是我一直告诉你的，
the spatial redundancy.
空间冗余。
Most images have this kind of redundancy,
大多数图像都有这种冗余，
which is spatial redundancy.
这就是空间冗余。
So, if you, in the image
所以，如果你在图中
domain, if you know this current pixel value, that means
域，如果你知道当前的像素值，那就意味着
you also know the pixel values around
你还知道周围的像素值
it, okay, from the
它，好吧，从
compression perspective, this is not
压缩角度来看，这不是
good. Why? Because you
好的。为什么？因为你
store lots of redundant,
存储大量冗余，
unnecessary information. For example,
不必要的信息。例如，
if you look at a 4x4 pixel block, if
如果你看一个 4x4 像素块，如果
all the pixel values are very similar to
所有像素值都非常相似
each other, why do I need to store
彼此，为什么我需要存储
all the pixel value?
所有像素值？
I just need to roughly store one pixel
我只需要大致存储一个像素
value, more or less can represent this block
value，或多或少可以代表这个块
already. So, therefore,
已经。所以，因此，
okay, if you are talking
好吧，如果你在说话
about image in the original
关于原文中的图像
image domain, it contains
图像域，它包含
a, right, okay,
一个，对，好吧，
knowing this particular
知道这个特殊的
pixel value means you also
像素值意味着你也
more or less can tell the pixel value
或多或少可以看出像素值
surrounding it. So, that means
围绕它。所以，这意味着
they actually have strong correlation.
它们实际上具有很强的相关性。
The pixel value,
像素值，
the current pixel value and its surrounding
当前像素值及其周围
pixel value has strong
像素值强
correlation. When they have strong
相关性。当他们拥有强大的
correlation, that means there's lots of redundancy.
相关性，这意味着存在大量冗余。
And when they have
当他们有
lots of redundancy, this is not good
大量冗余，这不好
from the compression
从压缩
perspective, because you have so much
观点，因为你有这么多
extra unnecessary information
额外的不必要的信息
that you are storing. Okay? So, that's
您正在存储的。好的？那么，那就是
what it states here.
它在这里说明了什么。
On the other hand, right, this particular
另一方面，对，这个特殊的
image in the original pixel
原始像素中的图像
domain, if you transform it
域，如果你转换它
into the transform domain, so in
进入变换域，所以在
the transform domain, you have some
变换域，你有一些
transform coefficient.
变换系数。
Right, so just based on what I
是的，所以只是根据我的情况
explained, do you think that in the transform
解释一下，你认为在变换中
domain now, knowing this
现在域，知道这一点
pixel value will tell you what is
像素值会告诉你什么是
the, knowing this coefficient
，知道这个系数
will tell you what is the
会告诉你什么是
coefficient next to it?
旁边的系数？
Chances are, no.
很可能，不。
Okay, in the transform domain now,
好的，现在在变换域中，
in the transform domain, you have lots
在变换域中，你有很多
of transform coefficient.
的变换系数。
So, if you know this transform coefficient,
所以，如果你知道这个变换系数，
it doesn't tell you much
它并没有告诉你太多
the transform coefficient next
接下来是变换系数
to it. So, this is
到它。所以，这是
actually good from the compression perspective.
从压缩的角度来看实际上很好。
Why? Because knowing
为什么？因为知道
this particular coefficient doesn't tell you
这个特定的系数不会告诉你
the coefficient around it. That means you
其周围的系数。这意味着你
remove lots of the redundant
去掉很多多余的
information already.
信息已经。
So, from the compression perspective,
所以，从压缩的角度来看，
that is good. Right, so again,
那很好。对了，再说一遍，
this is high level. Yeah, later on when
这是高水平的。是的，稍后当
we study DCT, we will give you
我们研究DCT，我们会给你
a lot more concrete example.
更多具体的例子。
But in short, what it means is that it offers
但简而言之，它的意思是它提供了
redundancy reduction.
减少冗余。
It reduces the correlation, or the
它降低了相关性，或者
similarity, okay, between
相似性，好吧，之间
the transform coefficient, just like what I mentioned.
变换系数，就像我提到的那样。
Now, in the transform domain, knowing this
现在，在变换域中，知道这一点
pixel value doesn't, knowing
像素值不会，知道
this coefficient doesn't tell you the
这个系数并没有告诉你
coefficient surrounding it.
围绕它的系数。
Okay, so which is good from
好的，那么哪个是好的
the compression perspective.
压缩的角度。
And then for this transform coding,
然后对于这个变换编码，
it's a reversible process.
这是一个可逆的过程。
That means the original
这意味着原来
signal can be obtained by applying
信号可以通过应用获得
the inverse transform. So, if you
逆变换。所以，如果你
have the data in the
有数据在
image domain, you can perform the
图像域，您可以执行
forward transform to get the transform
前向变换得到变换
coefficient. And for this particular
系数。而对于这个特殊的
transform coefficient, you can
变换系数，可以
take the inverse transform to recover
进行逆变换即可恢复
your original pixel.
你的原始像素。
So therefore, it's actually
因此，它实际上是
a reversible process.
一个可逆的过程。
That's what I mean by reversible
这就是我所说的可逆
process here.
在这里进行处理。
Right, okay, so let's look at some typical
好吧，让我们看一些典型的
transform-based image compression scheme.
基于变换的图像压缩方案。
Right, so there's many ways
是的，有很多方法
for you to perform image compression.
供您执行图像压缩。
So, transform-based image compression
因此，基于变换的图像压缩
is one of the most popular
是最受欢迎的之一
way to perform compression.
方式来执行压缩。
Right, so techniques such as
是的，所以诸如此类的技术
standards such as JPEG compression
标准，例如 JPEG 压缩
and MPEG compression is based
并且MPEG压缩是基于
on transform-based image compression.
基于变换的图像压缩。
So, what's the typical
那么，什么是典型的
pipelines of a transform-based
基于变换的管道
image compression?
图像压缩？
Right, so a typical transform-based image
是的，典型的基于变换的图像
compression consists of the following steps.
压缩由以下步骤组成。
Yes, image partitioning, transform,
是的，图像分割、变换、
quantization and coding.
量化和编码。
So, let's look at each of these steps a bit
那么，让我们稍微看一下每个步骤
more in detail. So, first of all,
更详细。所以，首先，
right, we have an input
对了，我们有一个输入
image, supposed to be an input image.
图像，应该是输入图像。
The first thing is that we do this
首先我们要做的是
particular partitioning. This image,
特定的分区。这个图像，
we partition it into
我们把它分成
numerous sub-images
许多子图像
or pixel blocks.
或像素块。
So, we can partition
所以，我们可以分区
to construct end-by-end
逐个构建
sub-image or pixel block.
子图像或像素块。
Right, okay, so and afterwards
好吧，那么，然后
for each of this sub-image or pixel block
对于每个子图像或像素块
we'll let it go through a forward
我们会让它通过前锋
transform. Okay, let me just
转换。好吧，让我
repeat. Given the image,
重复。鉴于图像，
we partition it into numerous
我们把它分成无数个
pixel block or sub-image.
像素块或子图像。
For each of this particular pixel block,
对于每个特定的像素块，
we can do the transformation
我们可以进行转型
to transform it into
将其转变为
the transform coefficient.
变换系数。
So, this is what it means
所以，这就是它的意思
by the forward transform.
通过前向变换。
So, this
所以，这个
pixel block,
像素块，
you do the transform, you have the transform
你做了转变，你就有了转变
coefficient now. So, this
现在的系数。所以，这个
transform coefficient next, you need to go through
接下来变换系数，需要经过
a quantizer here.
这里有一个量化器。
So, the objective of this
那么，本次活动的目的
particular quantizer is because
特定的量化器是因为
for our work,
为了我们的工作，
nowadays we are using
现在我们正在使用
a digital representation.
数字表示。
That means we are using computer
这意味着我们正在使用计算机
and computers are using some
和计算机正在使用一些
finite number of bits
有限位数
to represent it. So, right,
来代表它。所以，对吧，
when you do this
当你这样做时
forward transform, the value
正向变换，值
potentially are continuous value.
可能是连续值。
It's a continuous
这是一个连续的
value signal.
值信号。
But we are using computer to represent
但我们用计算机来表示
this data. So,
这个数据。所以，
when using computer, that means you are using
当使用计算机时，这意味着您正在使用
a finite number of bits.
有限数量的比特。
So, finite number of bits means that you can
因此，有限的位数意味着您可以
only have a finite number of levels
只有有限数量的级别
to represent it. Right, so,
来代表它。对了，所以，
therefore, in order to
因此，为了
be able to use only finite number of
只能使用有限数量的
levels to represent, we have to perform
水平来代表，我们必须执行
quantization. So,
量化。所以，
this quantizer is to perform
这个量化器要执行
the quantization, similar to
量化，类似于
any, you know, similar
任何，你知道，类似的
quantizer you have studied before.
你之前学过的量化器。
So, once you have quantized it,
所以，一旦你量化了它，
the output at this
此时的输出
particular junction is you have some symbol.
特定的连接点是你有一些符号。
So, you have some pattern.
所以，你有一些模式。
So, this pattern, now you have some patterns
所以，这个模式，现在你有一些模式
here. Some of these patterns will occur
这里。其中一些模式将会出现
more often than the others.
比其他人更频繁。
So, then, in your mind,
那么，在你心里，
right away you think, okay, if that's the case,
你立刻就会想，好吧，如果是这样的话，
then what I'm going to do is I'm going to use
那么我要做的就是使用
a symbol encoder,
符号编码器，
such as a Huffman coding, to
例如霍夫曼编码，
perform decompression. So, therefore,
执行减压。所以，因此，
this is the typical pipeline.
这是典型的管道。
Right, we have image, we partition into
对了，我们有图像，我们划分成
numerous pixel blocks or sub-image.
许多像素块或子图像。
Each of the blocks we let it go through
我们让它经过的每一个街区
a forward transform. We
前向变换。我们
let it go through a quantizer to quantize
让它通过量化器来量化
into a finite number of patterns.
分成有限数量的模式。
Okay, and then we use a symbol decoder,
好的，然后我们使用符号解码器，
because some patterns occur more often
因为某些模式出现的频率更高
than the others. We use some symbol decoder
比其他人。我们使用一些符号解码器
such as Huffman coding, right,
比如霍夫曼编码，对吧，
to convert it into
将其转换为
the bitstream. So, when you see this
比特流。所以，当你看到这个
compressed image, then it means that now
压缩图像，那么这意味着现在
you have a compressed bitstream already.
你已经有一个压缩的比特流了。
So, this is the
所以，这就是
encoder. So, encoder
编码器。所以，编码器
means that you take an image,
意味着你拍摄了一张照片，
right, after you have gone through this
是的，当你经历完这个之后
encoder, right, you will have
编码器，对，你会有
the compressed bitstream.
压缩的比特流。
Okay, it's much smaller.
好吧，它小了很多。
Right, so this particular figure now is a
是的，所以现在这个特定的数字是
decoder. So, the decoder means
解码器。所以，解码器意味着
that you have a compressed image
你有一个压缩图像
of bitstream, right, after you
比特流，对，在你之后
go through this decoder, you'll
通过这个解码器，你会
get your reconstructed
得到你的重建
or decompressed image.
或解压后的图像。
So, for this particular process here,
因此，对于这里的这个特定过程，
it's the reverse of this.
情况正好相反。
So, first you have the compressed image of
所以，首先你有压缩图像
bitstream, you let it go through the symbol
比特流，你让它通过符号
decoder. So, this is encoder,
解码器。所以，这是编码器，
this is decoder. Right, and
这是解码器。对了，还有
afterwards, actually there's a missing block here,
之后，实际上这里缺少一个块，
right, this textbook
对了，这本教科书
missed out this block. So, this block here,
错过了这个区块。所以，这里的这个街区，
this is quantizer, this is the de-quantizer.
这是量化器，这是去量化器。
It's just performing the reverse.
它只是执行相反的操作。
One of them you divide the other,
其中一个你将另一个分开，
one of them you divide the other, you multiply.
将其中一个相除，将另一个相乘。
Okay, this is a
好吧，这是一个
full transform, this is the inverse transform.
完全变换，这就是逆变换。
You partition it into numerous
你把它分成无数个
blocks, this you put the blocks
块，这是你放置的块
together. Right, so that's pretty much
一起。对了，这样就差不多了
the reverse of it. So,
其反面。所以，
this full transform, this is the inverse
这个完整的变换，这是逆变换
transform. Okay, so
转换。好吧，那么
next let's look at some of the
接下来让我们看一些
common transform.
共同变换。
So, okay, so for this common
那么，好吧，对于这个常见的
transform is that we apply a one-to-one
变换是我们应用一对一的
transform to the input data.
转换为输入数据。
So, this transformation is a
所以，这个转变是一个
one-to-one transformation. Okay,
一对一的转变。好的，
so why do we want to do the transform? I think we
那么我们为什么要进行转换呢？我想我们
mentioned it early on.
很早就提到过。
The reason why we want to perform the transform
我们要执行转换的原因
is the transform output is in
变换输出是在
a representation which is more
更具有代表意义
suitable for efficient compression
适合高效压缩
than the raw image data. So,
比原始图像数据。所以，
this point pretty much is what I mentioned.
这一点几乎就是我所提到的。
Yeah, once you have this particular
是的，一旦你有了这个特别的
small image
小图片
block, okay,
阻止，好吧，
when you do the transformation,
当你进行转换时，
once it's in this transform domain,
一旦进入这个变换域，
this transform domain, you know,
这个变换域，你知道，
has some good property that we can exploit
有一些我们可以利用的好特性
or its representation
或其代表
is more suitable for compression.
更适合压缩。
Yeah, okay, so
是啊，好吧，所以
among all those transform, one of the
在所有这些转变中，其中之一
most popular transform is the
最流行的变换是
DCT. Okay,
DCT。好的，
so DCT is a
所以 DCT 是
unitary mapping.
统一映射。
So, unitary mapping
所以，统一映射
means that this particular transform
意味着这个特定的变换
matrix, if you call this
矩阵，如果你称之为
transform matrix T,
变换矩阵 T，
then it's T, T-transposed
然后是 T，T 转置
is equal to T-transposed,
等于 T 转置，
T is equal to identity.
T 等于身份。
So, anyway, for those of you who study
所以，无论如何，对于那些学习的人来说
linear algebra, you
线性代数，你
know that this particular
知道这个特殊的
properties of unitary
单一性的性质
transformation.
转变。
Okay, so DCT is a
好的，所以 DCT 是
type of unitary
单一类型
mapping. So, later on, when we
映射。所以，后来，当我们
study about how do we perform
研究我们的表现
this DCT will become clear.
这个DCT将会变得清晰。
So, DCT has a good property
因此，DCT具有良好的性能
because it can pack the energy
因为它可以储存能量
into a small number of kVc.
变成少量的kVc。
So, just like what I mentioned
所以，就像我提到的那样
earlier on, so if you look at
早些时候，所以如果你看看
a small pixel block, we do not know
一个小像素块，我们不知道
where the energy is located.
能量所在的地方。
But after you use a DCT
但是当你使用DCT之后
transform, the energy will be packed
转变，能量将被压缩
into a small number of kVc.
变成少量的kVc。
So, once we can pack into a small number
所以，一旦我们可以打包成一个小数量
of kVc, then we can pay our
kVc，那么我们可以支付我们的
attention to try to represent
注意尝试代表
data for this
这方面的数据
small number of kVc.
kVc 数少。
So, there are some
所以，有一些
well-known transforms,
众所周知的变换，
which include, for
其中包括，对于
example, some of the well-known transforms.
例如，一些众所周知的变换。
It's a DFT,
这是一个 DFT，
discrete Fourier Transform,
离散傅里叶变换，
discrete Cosine Transform, discrete
离散余弦变换，离散
Wave Flare Transform. So, these are some of the
波耀斑变换。所以，这些是一些
popular transforms that have been used.
已使用的流行变换。
But for JPEG
但对于 JPEG
and MPAC, we will be using
和 MPAC，我们将使用
this DCT. That's why we will
这个 DCT。这就是为什么我们会
study, our key focus will be studying
学习，我们的重点是学习
on this. This
关于这一点。这
DWT is used in JPEG
JPEG 中使用 DWT
2000, right? Actually,
2000，对吗？实际上，
now it's less commonly used.
现在已经不太常用了。
That's why we will not touch on it. We will
这就是为什么我们不会触及它。我们将
only be focusing on this DCT
只关注这个 DCT
transform. And then, based on
转换。然后，基于
this DCT transform, then we will explain
这个DCT变换，然后我们将解释
all those properties that we have just mentioned.
我们刚才提到的所有这些属性。
So, just now, this slide here is pretty
所以，刚才，这张幻灯片很漂亮
much explaining about this transform
关于这个转变的很多解释
block. So, the next
堵塞。那么，接下来
block that we have is the quantization.
我们拥有的块是量化。
So, as I mentioned, the objective
所以，正如我提到的，目标
of quantization is that you want to generate
量化是你想要生成
a small number of symbols
少量符号
from the transform coefficient.
从变换系数。
Because, alright,
因为，好吧，
after you have performed this
执行此操作后
transform, the output, right, so
变换，输出，对，所以
for example, the signal
例如，信号
at this particular junction is
在这个特定的交界处是
4x4 pixel block.
4x4 像素块。
After you have performed the transform,
执行转换后，
what you have is a 4x4, for example,
例如，您拥有一辆 4x4
transform coefficients
变换系数
here. So, this transform
这里。所以，这个变换
coefficients, their values are
系数，它们的值为
continuous value.
连续值。
So, therefore, if you want to use
因此，如果您想使用
a computer to represent,
一台计算机来代表，
we must perform quantization.
我们必须进行量化。
So, it's to generate
所以，它是为了生成
a finite number of symbols from the
有限数量的符号
transform coefficient. Because transform
变换系数。因为改造
coefficient initially is continuous value.
系数最初是连续值。
So, we need to perform quantization.
因此，我们需要进行量化。
So, it's irreversible
所以，这是不可逆转的
many-to-one mapping causing information
多对一映射导致信息
loss. So, for many of you
损失。所以，对于你们很多人来说
who have studied your undergrad before, you
谁曾经学习过你的本科生，你
know that once you perform quantization,
知道一旦你执行量化，
information will be lost.
信息将会丢失。
So, information, when information is lost,
所以，信息，当信息丢失时，
that means it's an irreversible process.
这意味着这是一个不可逆转的过程。
So, what it means is that
那么，它的意思就是
if you look at this simple scalar
如果你看这个简单的标量
quantization, your horizontal
量化，你的水平
axis is the input and the vertical axis
axis 是输入，纵轴
is the output. So, suppose
是输出。所以，假设
if your input is in this
如果你的输入是这样的
range here, you can see the input
范围在这里，你可以看到输入
in this range here will be mapped
在这个范围内这里将被映射
to this same output of 0.5.
到同样的输出 0.5。
For this range of input,
对于这个输入范围，
okay, this range of input
好的，这个输入范围
here will be mapped to this output value
这里将被映射到这个输出值
of 0.5. So, that means when you do that,
0.5。所以，这意味着当你这样做时，
it's a many-to-one mapping.
这是一个多对一的映射。
Many value from here
这里有很多价值
will be mapped to this single output
将被映射到这个单一输出
value. So, it's a many-to-one
价值。所以，这是一个多对一
mapping. When you do that,
映射。当你这样做时，
that means some information has been lost
这意味着一些信息已经丢失
already. Why do we say some information has
已经。为什么我们说有些信息有
been lost? Because now
迷路了？因为现在
you know the output is 0.5,
你知道输出是 0.5，
can you recover what is your
你能恢复你的东西吗
original input? You cannot. You do
原始输入？你不能。你做
not know which of this
不知道这是哪一个
input value mapped to this output.
映射到该输出的输入值。
So, therefore, you can see quite clearly
所以，因此，你可以很清楚地看到
from this particular example, it's a
从这个特定的例子来看，这是一个
many-to-one mapping,
多对一映射，
and some information has been lost
并且一些信息已经丢失
already because input value within this
已经因为输入值在此
range will be mapped to this output
范围将映射到此输出
value. So, from these output values
价值。所以，从这些输出值
of 0.5, you cannot recover
0.5，则无法恢复
your original input.
您的原始输入。
If that happened,
如果发生这种情况，
that means some information has been lost.
这意味着一些信息已经丢失。
So, these are some, two examples
所以，这是一些、两个例子
of the scalar
标量的
quantization just to illustrate
量化只是为了说明
the point.
重点。
Right, okay. So, now we have gone through
对了，好吧。所以，现在我们已经经历了
the, we have explained about
我们已经解释过
this quantization already.
这个量化已经。
So, the last one is a symbol
所以最后一个是一个符号
encoder.
编码器。
So, the symbol encoder,
所以，符号编码器，
as I mentioned, after you
正如我提到的，在你之后
have done the quantization,
已经做了量化，
so, very often, some pattern
所以，很多时候，一些模式
will occur more often than the others.
会比其他情况更频繁地发生。
So, once you hear that some patterns
所以，一旦你听到一些模式
occur more than the others,
比其他情况出现得更多，
that means you know that for different patterns, there are
这意味着您知道对于不同的模式，有
some probability distribution.
一些概率分布。
So, when there are some probability distribution,
因此，当存在某种概率分布时，
some pattern occur more than the others,
某些模式比其他模式出现得更多，
then right away, you know, you have to
然后马上，你知道，你必须
use techniques such as entropy and coding
使用熵和编码等技术
to compress it,
来压缩它，
because it's more efficient.
因为它更有效率。
So, this coding part, the objective is to
所以，这个编码部分的目标是
assign a code word of
分配一个代码字
patterns to each symbol
每个符号的图案
at the
在
output of the quantization.
量化的输出。
So, you can, of course, you can choose
所以，你当然可以，你可以选择
to use a fixed length or variable length
使用固定长度或可变长度
coding, but nowadays, you already know,
编码，但如今，你已经知道，
after you have studied the first part, you know
当你学完第一部分之后，你就知道了
that variable length coding is definitely
可变长度编码肯定是
a much better choice.
一个更好的选择。
So, the idea of variable length coding
所以，变长编码的思想
or entropy coding is
或者熵编码是
like what we mentioned before, you assign
就像我们之前提到的，你分配
the code in such a way,
代码以这种方式，
such that the average length of the
这样的平均长度
code word will be reduced.
码字将会减少。
So, those more probable
那么，那些更有可能的
symbols or more common symbols, you assign
符号或更常见的符号，您指定
shorter code word.
较短的码字。
Those less probable symbols, you assign
那些不太可能的符号，你分配
a longer code word, so that overall,
更长的码字，所以总的来说，
the aim is that the average
目标是平均
number of bits per symbol is reduced.
每个符号的位数减少。
So, this is achieved
那么，这就实现了
by assigning shorter code word
通过分配较短的码字
to more probable symbol,
更可能的符号，
and this is the fundamental principle
这是基本原则
of entropy and coding, such as
熵和编码的关系，例如
half-moon coding that we have studied.
我们研究过的半月编码。
So, I think
所以，我认为
we'll probably stop today.
我们今天可能会停下来。
So, that was...
那么，那是...
Thank you.
谢谢。
I'll see you next week.
下周见。
I'll take it down for you.
我会帮你把它取下来。
Okay.
好的。
This sigma s square is
这个西格玛平方是
according to its description,
根据其描述，
it's more like the average to the power of q.
它更像是 q 次方的平均值。
But according to this formula,
但根据这个公式，
it's more like the variance.
它更像是方差。
So, I wonder what you mean.
所以，我想知道你的意思。
This is a signal.
这是一个信号。
This is not a noise.
这不是噪音。
This one is x.
这个是x.
So, this is the signal.
所以，这就是信号。
This is the signal.
这就是信号。
This is not a noise.
这不是噪音。
This one is x.
这个是x.
So, in the pixel,
所以，在像素中，
in the pixel,
在像素中，
if you talk about image
如果你谈论图像
as an example,
举个例子，
so, image has different pixel values.
因此，图像具有不同的像素值。
So, that means what? Each of the pixel values
那么，这意味着什么？每个像素值
is squared.
是平方的。
Each of the pixel values
每个像素值
is squared,
是平方，
and afterwards, you take the average.
然后取平均值。
So, yeah.
所以，是的。
The term below is a noise.
下面的术语是噪音。
Okay.
好的。
So, it's more like...
所以，它更像是...
It's more like this one?
是不是更像这个呢？
Yes.
是的。
Okay. Thank you.
好的。谢谢。
So, what's x, d indicate
那么，x、d 表示什么
in the
在
peak signal
峰值信号
signal-noise ratio?
信噪比？
So,
所以，
as it is, I just pick
事实上，我只是选择
signal to noise, right? Pick signal
信噪比，对吗？拣选信号
means that the largest
意味着最大的
value in the
值在
original sequence of the signal.
信号的原始序列。
Okay. So, suppose
好的。所以，假设
if you take the...
如果你采取...
This signal-noise ratio is
该信噪比为
a common matrix used in
一个常用的矩阵用于
measuring the quality for image
测量图像质量
restoration.
恢复。
So, for image,
所以，对于图像来说，
for example,
例如，
if you talk about grayscale first,
如果你先谈谈灰度，
so, grayscale, each pixel, you use 8 bits
所以，灰度，每个像素，你使用8位
to represent. So, that means
代表。所以，这意味着
it's possible values from 0 to 255.
可能的值从 0 到 255。
So, this peak value is
所以，这个峰值就是
255. So, therefore, the number on top is
255. 因此，上面的数字是
255 squared.
255平方。
I know.
我知道。
I have a question
我有一个问题
that's not relevant to the course.
这与课程无关。
Because my
因为我的
annual project is
年度项目是
a newer system of
一个较新的系统
EMT. I'm a year-old student.
急救人员。我是一名七岁的学生。
And I see
我明白了
he informed me there's a
他告诉我有一个
joint PT with Shanghai Jiao Tong.
与上海交通联合PT。
For
为了
PT.
PT。
For him? Yeah, for him. I also see your name
为了他？是的，为了他。我也看到你的名字
there. The question is
那里。问题是
it's not the topic.
这不是主题。
It's just his annual project. You really don't know
这只是他的年度项目。你真的不知道
so much information.
这么多信息。
I don't know if you have any connection
不知道你有没有什么联系
or existing PT students
或现有的 PT 学生
who like under this program.
谁喜欢下这个计划。
Who is the supervisor?
监督者是谁？
I mean, the
我的意思是，
I still don't quite understand what's the question
我还是不太明白问题是什么
you're trying to ask. I just want to ask
你想问。我只是想问
if there's any existing students
如果有现有的学生
who under this joint PT program,
在这个联合 PT 计划下，
like, I want to ask him
比如说，我想问他
if there's some
如果有一些
questions about the degree
关于学位的问题
verification for Chinese, because
对于中文的验证，因为
we need the distribution system.
我们需要分配系统。
Oh, so you're saying
哦，所以你是说
is there are there some other
还有其他的吗
seniors who have actually gone through this
真正经历过这个事情的前辈
kind of program before?
之前有什么样的节目？
My prof is a new prof, so I think he
我的教授是一位新教授，所以我认为他
don't have that cut out. Actually this program is
没有那个剪掉。其实这个程序是
very new. This is also the first time
很新。这也是第一次
I'm doing it. Yeah, so it's a very new
我正在做。是的，所以这是一个非常新的
program. So if you have such
程序。所以如果你有这样的
a question, the best is to ask the office.
有问题，最好去问办公室。
They even show me the sample of the degree.
他们甚至给我看了学位样本。
But
但
we cannot say like for
我们不能说喜欢
the site of China, if they verify
中国的网站，如果他们核实的话
like a foreign or local.
就像外国人或当地人一样。
So I know the US have
所以我知道美国有
a connection with them
与他们有联系
for a long time, but NTU is
很长一段时间了，但 NTU 是
from...
从...
There are some universities
有一些大学
that we have some collaboration
我们有一些合作
for, like, Tsinghua.
比如清华大学。
Yeah, this Tsinghua
是的，这个清华
collaboration with Tsinghua has been ongoing
与清华大学的合作一直在进行
for some time already.
已经有一段时间了。
But other
但其他
universities like
大学喜欢
Shanghai, Jiangtong, De1,
上海、江通、De1、
or at least this is the first time I see
或者至少这是我第一次看到
it. Yeah.
它。是的。
Yeah, so, but I know it's
是的，所以，但我知道这是
pretty new.
很新。
So therefore, again,
因此，再次，
I think this
我认为这个
kind of question is definitely hard for me to answer.
这样的问题对我来说肯定很难回答。
I cannot answer that.
我无法回答这个问题。
So far, at least for myself,
到目前为止，至少对我自己来说，
is that I don't have...
是我没有...
I'm not aware of any
我不知道有任何
senior who have
高级谁有
gone through this program yet.
已经完成这个程序了。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
I have another
我还有另一个
question.
问题。
So how
那么如何
I can comprehend
我能理解
that the
那
entropy
熵
can indicate the
可以表明
smallest number of bits
最小位数
necessary to
有必要
do the encoding?
进行编码？
Okay.
好的。
So this entropy,
所以这个熵，
this term, actually, loosely
这个词实际上是松散的
speaking, they are using...
说起来，他们正在使用...
they are more commonly used in communication theory.
它们在传播理论中更常用。
Yeah.
是的。
So in the communication theory,
所以在传播理论中，
it's an indication of the degree
这是学位的标志
of randomness and how
随机性以及如何
much information is contained
包含很多信息
in the source.
在源中。
But in the context of our
但在我们的背景下
compression
压缩
perspective, this entropy,
角度来看，这个熵，
if you have a data source that
如果您有一个数据源
consists of different symbols,
由不同的符号组成，
but you can calculate its entropy.
但你可以计算它的熵。
When you calculate the entropy,
当你计算熵时，
this number actually
这个数字实际上
indicates to you what is the smallest
告诉你最小的是什么
number of bits
位数
per symbol that you
每个符号你
can use to represent
可以用来表示
a symbol.
一个符号。
So it's
所以这是
easy to understand. For example, you have
容易理解。例如，你有
a symbol. You can always use more bits
一个符号。您始终可以使用更多位
to represent. You can use three...
代表。您可以使用三个...
I mean, you can use eight bits, you can use
我的意思是，你可以使用八位，你可以使用
ten bits, you can use twenty bits. More is
十位，你可以使用二十位。更多的是
okay. But when you try to
好的。但当你尝试
use what is the smallest
使用最小的
number of bits that you can use
您可以使用的位数
to represent this symbol,
来表示这个符号，
there's a theoretical lower
理论上有一个较低的值
bound. So this theoretical lower bound
边界。所以这个理论下界
is the entropy
是熵
from the context of compression.
从压缩的上下文来看。
Okay.
好的。
So
所以
.
。